古巴 关达那摩湾 美国海军基地
义海雄风
齐步走！
Forward march!
我请求
I'm requesting...
上校，我想请求由我担任律师
Captain, I'd like to request that it be me who's the attorney...
这是我自己决定的
That it be myself who's assigned.
不行，我想请求指任我作
No, I'd like to request that it be I who am assigned...
“这是我的决定”？
"That it be I who am assigned"?
这样不错，显得信心十足
That's good. That's confidence-inspiring.
措辞也很得体
Good grammar there.
上校，我想请求指任我为律师
Captain, I'd like to request...
华盛顿哥伦比亚特区  法务总监办事处
that I be the attorney assigned.
嗨，我是盖洛维少校，来这见威斯特上校
I'm Lieutenant Commander Galloway here to see Captain West.
快进去吧，少校，他们正等着你
Go right in, Commander. They're expecting you.
谢谢
Thank you.
乔，快进来 谢谢，长官
Jo, come on in. Thank you, sir.
威斯特上校，这就是盖洛维少校
Captain West, this is Lieutenant Commander Galloway.
乔，你认识劳伦斯少校吧？ 是的，长官
Jo, you know Commander Lawrence. Yes, sir.
上校，很感谢你这么快就接见我
Captain, I appreciate you seeing me on such short notice.
干嘛不坐下？ 不用，长官
Would you like to sit down? I'm fine, sir.
坐吧 好的
Have a seat. Okay.
我听说上周末在古巴出了麻烦是吧？
I understand we had some trouble over the weekend down in Cuba?
是的，长官，上周五有两名海军陆战队员
Yes, sir. This past Friday, two Marines...
准下士哈罗德・道森 和一等兵劳登・多尼
a Lance Corporal Harold Dawson and a Private Louden Downey...
进入一等兵威廉・圣地亚哥的营房 并殴打了他
entered the barracks room of a P.F.C. William Santiago and assaulted him.
大约一小时后圣地亚哥在基地医院身亡
Santiago died at the base hospital approximately an hour later.
负责给道森和多尼录取口供 的海军调查处官员…
The N.I.S. Agent who took Dawson and Downey's statements...
认定他们是想试图阻止圣地亚哥…
maintains they were trying to prevent Santiago...
举报道森在界线上的开枪事件
from naming Dawson in a fenceline shooting incident.
已安排今天下午四点 在基地举行一次听证会
They're scheduled to have a hearing down in Cuba this afternoon at 16:00.
问题在哪？ 道森和多尼…
What's the problem? Dawson and Downey...
都是模范海军陆战队员 而圣地亚哥是有名的落后分子
are both recruiting poster Marines, and Santiago was known to be a screwup.
我猜这多半是一次“红色条规”
I was thinking it sounded an awful lot like a Code Red.
老天
Christ.
长官，我希望将他们移交华盛顿 并为他们指派一名
Sir, I'd like to have them moved up to Washington and assigned counsel...
能认真调查此事
someone who can really look into this...
不仅精通法律技巧…
someone who possesses not only the legal skill...
而且熟知军队内部运作方式的律师
but a familiarity with the inner workings of the military.
简而言之，上校，我提议…
In short, Captain, I'd like to suggest that...
由我来担任
I be the one who that...
指派我作他们的辩护律师
that it be me who is assigned to represent them... myself.
盖洛维少校，你要不要来杯咖啡？
Commander Galloway, why don'tyou get yourself a cup of coffee?
谢谢，长官，不用
Thank you, sir. I'm fine.
我希望你能回避一下好让我们私下谈谈
I'd like you to leave the room so we can talk about you behind your back.
没问题，长官
Certainly, sir.
我还以为再也不会有什么“红色条规”了
I thought this Code Red shit wasn't going on anymore.
海军远在关达那摩 谁知道在那有些什么鬼事？
With the Marines at Gitmo, who knows what the hell goes on down there?
我们最好在其他人知道之前查清楚
We better find out before the rest of the world does.
这种鬼事有可能弄得无法收拾
Damn thing could get messy.
好吧，这个盖洛维少校怎么样？
All right, what about this Commander Galloway?
她在内政部担任文职人员…
She's been working a desk in Internal Affairs...
有一年多了
for a little over a year now.
之前呢？ 两年内办过三个案子
Before that? Disposed of three cases in two years.
两年三件案子？罗森博格叛国案吗？
Three cases in two years? Who's she handling, the Rosenbergs?
她不适合做首席律师 但绝对是个好调查员
She's not cut out for litigation. She's a hell of an investigator.
她在内政部协助律师工作非常尽力
In Internal Affairs she can crawl up a lawyer's ass with the best of them.
但到了庭讯的时候 我知道，心有余而力不足
But when it comes to trial work... I know. All passion, no street smarts.
叫她进来吧
Bring her back in.
少校，我们明早就将被告转到这里来
Commander, we're gonna have the defendants moved up here in the morning.
谢谢，长官 师部会给他们指派律师
Thankyou, sir. Division will assign them counsel.
但…不是我 根据你的同事对你的评价…
But not me. From what I get from your colleagues...
由你担任此事太过大材小用…
you're much too valuable in your present assignment to be wasted...
我相信此案无非是几分钟的庭辩…
in what I'm sure will boil down to a five-minute plea bargain...
以及一个礼拜的文书工作
and a week's worth of paperwork.
长官，我想恐怕没这么简单
Sir, I think there might be more involved than that.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
我保证师部会为此指派合适的人选
I promise you Division will assign the right man for the job.
好了，来吧，拿下二垒
All right. Let's go. Let's get two.
抱歉 用不着抱歉，切比
Sorry. Nothing to be sorry about, Sherby.
你只要把球接住就行
You just look the ball into your glove.
第二投
Shooting two.
对不起 你得相信我，切比
Sorry. You gotta trust me, Sherby.
你只要集中精神就能提高接住的成功率
Keep your eyes open, your chances of catching it increase by a factor often.
凯菲 我们再试试
Kaffee. Let's try it again.
戴维，你精神失常吗？
Dave, you seem distraught.
麦德摩的案子 我们约好在十五分钟前会面的
We were supposed to meet 15 minutes ago about the McDermott case.
你是在拖延时间，现在我们马上着手…
You're stalling on this thing. Now we either do it now...
不然我就把你的当事人送上他妈的绞架
or, no kidding, Kaffee, I'm gonna hang your boy from a fucking yardarm!
绞架？切比，海军还在用绞架行刑吗？
Yardarm? Sherby, does the Navy still hang people from yardarms?
我看不会
I don't think so.
戴维，切比认为海军不会再采用绞刑
Dave, Sherby doesn't think the Navy hangs people from yardarms anymore.
我要指控他藏毒并在值勤期间吸毒
I'm gonna charge him with possession and being under the influence on duty.
你劝他认罪的话 我可以建议判他三十天监禁
You plead guilty, I'll recommend 30 days in the brig with loss of rank and pay.
那是“牛至”，戴维 只值十美元的调味品
It was oregano, Dave. It was $10 worth of oregano.
可他认为是大麻
Yeah, well, your client thought it was marijuana.
我的当事人是个傻瓜，但傻并不违法
My client's a moron. That's not against the law.
凯菲，我同样得给上面一个交代 我必须起诉他
Kaffee, I got people to answer to just like you do. I'm gonna charge him.
告他私藏调味品吗？
With what, possession of a condiment?
凯菲 我很想帮你了结此事…
Kaffee. I tried to help you out of this...
但说到监禁时间，我会申请撤诉
but if you ask for jail time, I'm gonna file a motion to dismiss.
你办不到 我会办到的
You won't get it. I will get it.
如果法官拒绝，我会申请…
And if the M.T.D. Is denied, I'll file a motion...
要求作一次预先取证
seeking to obtain an evidentiary ruling in advance.
然后反对审前监禁
And after that, I'm gonna file against pretrial confinement.
而你得花上三个月来做书面材料…
And you're gonna spend the next three months going blind on paperwork...
就因为一名二等通信兵购买并吸食调味品
because a signalman second-class bought and smoked a dime bag of oregano.
再来，拿下二垒
Let's go! Let's get two!
Ｂ级轻罪，二十天监禁
B misdemeanor, 20 days in the brig.
Ｃ级轻罪，十五天受限处罚
C misdemeanor, 15 days restricted duty.
不知道我凭什么要接受
I don't know why I'm agreeing to this.
因为你比一般人要明智
'Cause you have wisdom beyond your years.
早
Morning.
早，上校
Morning, Captain.
孩子怎么样，山姆？
How's the baby, Sam?
她大概随时在准备说出她的第一句话
I think she's getting ready to say her first word any day now.
你怎么知道？
How can you tell?
她看起来象有什么话要说
She just looks like she has something to say.
不好意思，抱歉我来晚了
Excuse me. I'm sorry I'm late.
我知道你没什么好借口…
It's all right, Danny. I know you don't have a good excuse...
所以不会强迫你找个坏借口
so I won't force you to come up with a bad one.
谢谢，长官 第一件事与你有关
Thank you, sir. This first one's for you.
看来你要飞黄腾达了
Seems you're moving up in the world.
是师部要人
Been requested by Division.
要我去哪？
Requested to do what?
古巴，关达那摩湾
Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.
一名叫道森的海军准下士 非法使用所持武器…
A Marine corporal named Dawson illegally fires a round from his weapon...
向界线另一边的古巴境内开枪
over the fenceline and into Cuban territory.
什么“界线”？ 山姆
What's a fenceline? Sam.
是一堵把好人和坏人分隔开来的高墙
A big wall separating the good guys from the bad guys.
好学生 一等兵威廉・圣地亚哥…
Teacher's pet. P.F.C. William Santiago...
威胁要向海军调查部门举报道森
threatens to rat on Dawson to Naval Investigative Service.
道森和他的另一名队友…
Dawson and another member of his squad...
一等兵劳登・多尼 进入圣地亚哥的房间…
P.F.C. Louden Downey, go into Santiago's room...
把他捆了起来，在他喉咙里塞了块抹布…
tie him up, stuff a rag down his throat...
一小时后，圣地亚哥死了
and an hour later, Santiago's dead.
主治医师说那块抹布经过了某种毒药处理
Attending physician says the rag was treated with some kind of toxin.
他们下的毒？
They poisoned it?
他们矢口否认 都说了些什么？
Not according to them. What did they say?
没说太多，他们明天会乘飞机过来…
Not much. They're being flown up here tomorrow...
周三凌晨六点，你要去古巴呆一天…
and on Wednesday at 0600, you'll catch a transport down to Cuba for the day...
看能找到些什么
to find out what you can.
同时，去见见隶属内政部的 乔安妮・盖洛维少校
Meantime, go and see Lieutenant Commander Joanne Galloway... with Internal Affairs.
有问题吗？
Any questions?
去古巴的飞机…是在早上六点吗，长官？
Uh, the flight to Cuba... Was that 0600 in the morning, sir?
看来重点在于师部要依条例行事
Seems important to Division that this one be handled by the book.
所以要我指派辩护律师，有没有志愿者？
So I'm assigning co-counsel. Any volunteers?
不，我手头的案子太多了
I got a stack of papers on my desk about a mile high.
去帮帮凯菲吧 去干什么？
Work with Kaffee on this. Doing what?
凯菲只要四天就能摆平
Kaffee will have this done in about four days.
做些管理方面的事
Doing various administrative things.
备份什么的
Backup, whatever.
换句话说，就是我没有任何责任了
In other words, I have no responsibilities here whatsoever.
没错
Right.
正合我意
My kind of case.
对
Right.
好的，但我要周三才能拿到报告
Okay, but I've got to have that report by Wednesday.
嗨 稍等一下，嗨
Hi. Hold on. Hi.
丹尼・凯菲，我是来见
Daniel Kaffee. I was told to me with, uh...
盖洛维少校的
Lieutenant Commander Galloway.
来了解一下情况
About a briefing?
我回头打给你
I'll call you back.
你是师部指定的律师？
You're the attorney Division assigned?
我是首席律师，这是山姆
I'm lead counsel. This is Sam Weinberg.
我对此事不负任何责任
I have no responsibilities here whatsoever.
进来吧，请坐
Come in, please. Have a seat.
中尉，你在海军服役多久了？
Lieutenant, how long have you been in the Navy?
快九个月了
Going on nine months now.
你从律师学校毕业多久了？
And how long have you been out of law school?
一年多一点
A little over a year.
明白了
I see.
我做错什么了吗？
Have I done something wrong?
不，只是我请求师部指派律师时…
It's just that when I petition Division to have counsel assigned...
还指望会被认真对待
I was hoping I'd be taken seriously.
恕我冒昧，实际上确实如此
No offense taken, in case you were wondering.
凯菲中尉被公认是 我们部门最会打官司的人
Commander, Lieutenant Kaffee is generally... considered the best litigator in our office.
九个月内他成功地处理过四十四起案件
He's successfully plea-bargained 44 cases in nine months.
再多一件就能奖一套牛排刀
One more, I get a set of steak knives.
你上过庭吗？
Have you ever been in a courtroom?
驾照被吊销时上过一次
I once had my driver's license suspended.
以我的看法，如果闹上法庭…
Commander, from what I understand, if this thing goes to court...
他们需要的就不是律师而是牧师
they won't need a lawyer, they'll need a priest.
不，他们需要的是律师
No, they'll need a lawyer.
已经联系过道森的家人
Dawson's family's been contacted.
多尼最亲近的人是他姨妈詹妮・米勒
Downey's closest living relative is Ginny Miller, his aunt.
还没和她联系过，需要我来处理吗？
She hasn't been contacted yet. Would you like me to take care of that?
如果你愿意的话
If you feel like it.
你到那要见的人…
One of the people you'll be seeing down there...
是基地指挥官内森・杰赛普上校
is the barracks C.O., Colonel Nathan Jessup.
我猜你也听说过他
I assume you've heard of him.
谁没听说过呢？
Who hasn't?
他最近上了报，可能被任命为…
He's been in the papers lately. He's expected to be appointed...
国家安全委员会的执行主管
director of operations of National Security Council.
是吗？ 这些信…
Really? These are the letters...
是圣地亚哥在关达那摩写的
that Santiago wrote in his eight months at Gitmo.
就是关达那摩湾 我知道
That's Guantanamo Bay. I knew that one.
他曾写给舰队司令 写给海军指挥部的指挥官…
He wrote to the fleet commander to the commandant of the Marine Corps.
甚至议员，他希望能调离基地
Even his senator. He wanted to be transferred off the base.
但没人理会，你在听吗？
No one was listening. Are you with me? Yeah.
最后，他写给海军调查处…
Finally, he wrote to the Naval Investigative Service...
以提供道森准下士非法开枪的资料…
where he offered information about Corporal Dawson's fenceline shooting...
作为调动的交换条件
in exchange for a transfer.
很好，就这些吗？
Right. Is that all?
中尉，这些信似乎提供了…
Lieutenant, this letter makes it look like...
你当事人杀害圣地亚哥的动机
your client had a motive to kill Santiago.
明白了，圣地亚哥是谁？
Got you. And Santiago is who?
被害人
The victim.
写下来，可否假设这些信…
Write that down. Am I correct to assume these letters...
描述的并非关达那摩的光彩之处呢？
don't paint a flattering picture of Marine Corps life at Guantanamo Bay?
对，在 进一步地假设…
Yes, among... Am I further right in assuming...
调查此事有没有可能 令安全委员会的人难堪呢？
investigation of this incident might embarrass the Security Council guy?
杰赛普上校 十二年
Colonel Jessup. Twelve years.
什么？
Sorry?
争取判为共谋及行为不当
I'll get them to drop the conspiracy and conduct unbecoming.
刑期十二年
Twelve years.
你没和证人谈过也没看过一页档案
You haven't talked to a witness or looked at a piece of paper.
很意外，对吧？
Pretty impressive, huh?
你应该深入调查
You're gonna have to go deeper than that.
你有什么权限是我应该知道的？
Do you have some sort of jurisdiction here that I should know about?
我的工作就是确保你干好你的工作
My job is to make sure that you do your job.
我是内政部的特别律师…
I'm special counsel for Internal Affairs...
所以我的权限可说就是看着你
so my jurisdiction's pretty much in your face.
看看这些信 希望你从古巴回来能向我汇报
Read the letters. I'll expect your report when you return from Cuba.
当然 你可以走了
Sure. You're dismissed.
我总是忘了这个部分
I always forget that part.
他有点分心
He's a little preoccupied.
下周要和贝赛斯塔医院队比赛
Team's playing Bethesda Medical next week.
告诉他在那可别抖机灵
Tell your friend not to get cute down there.
关达那摩的海军可不好惹
The Marines in Guantanamo are fanatical.
哪方面？
About what?
海军方面
About being Marines.
尊敬的长官…
Dear sir...
我是一等兵威廉・Ｔ・圣地亚哥
my name is P.F.C. William T. Santiago.
是隶属海军陆战队Ｗ步兵警卫连二Ｂ排 的一名海军陆战队员
I'm a Marine stationed at Marine barracks... Rifle Security Company Windward, Second Platoon Bravo.
我写信是想告知您 我在古巴单位上遇到的麻烦…
I'm writing to inform you of my problems with my unit here in Cuba...
并请求您的帮助
and to ask for your help.
我之前曾因某种原因在训练时晕倒…
I've fallen out on runs before for several reasons...
感觉象是头晕或恶心
such as feeling dizzy or nauseated.
但在五月十八日，从一座小石山下来时 我落后了大约二到三十码
But on May 18, I'd fallen back about 20 or 30 yards... going down a rocky unstable hill.
我的中士抓住我并把我向山下推
My sergeant grabbed me and pushed me down the hill.
然后我眼前一黑，摔倒在地上
Then I saw all black, and the last thing I remembered was hitting the deck.
到医院后我被告知只是中暑而已
I was brought to the hospital where I was told I just had heat exhaustion.
我请求您帮助我
I ask you to help me.
求您，长官，我想要调离步兵警卫连
Please, sir. I just need to be transferred out of R.S.C.
美国海军陆战队一等兵 威廉・Ｔ・圣地亚哥 谨启
Sincerely, P.F.C. William T. Santiago... U.S. Marine Corps.
另附，作为我调离基地的交换条件…
P.S. In exchange for my transfer off the base...
我可以向您提供有关
I'm willing to provide you with information about...
“八月二日夜间向境外非法开枪事件” 的信息
"The illegal fenceline shooting that occurred the night of August 2."
这个该死的一等兵 威廉・圣地亚哥是什么人？
Who the fuck is P.F.C. William T. Santiago?
是隶属第二Ｂ排的一名一等兵，长官
Private Santiago is a member of Second Platoon Bravo, sir.
是吗，他似乎在“香格里拉” 呆得很不开心啊…
Yeah. Well, apparently he's not very happy down here in Shangri-la...
因为他给圣诞老人之外的所有人写信 请求调离
because he's written letters to everybody but Santa Claus... asking for a transfer.
而且还要披露一桩违纪开枪事件
And now he's telling tales about a fenceline shooting.
马修？
Matthew?
我感到震惊，长官
I'm appalled, sir.
你感到震惊
You're appalled.
这小子越级上报还出卖自己的队友…
This kid broke the chain of command and ratted on a member of his unit...
谎称他作为一名海军陆战队员…
to say nothing of the fact that he is a U.S. Marine...
就算没有中暑虚脱，似乎也无法参加训练
and it would appear he can't run from here to there... without collapsing from heat exhaustion.
Ｂ排是他妈的怎么回事，马修？
What the fuck is going on in Bravo Company, Matthew?
上校，我想这事最好还是等私下再谈
Colonel, I think it would be better to hold this discussion in private.
没必要，上校，我可以处理好这事，长官
That won't be necessary, Colonel. I can handle the situation, sir.
象你处理柯蒂斯・贝尔那样吗？ 别打断我，上尉
The same way you handled Curtis Bell? Don't interrupt me, Lieutenant!
我还是你的上级 而我是你的上级，马修
I'm still your superior officer. And I'm yours, Matthew.
我想知道我们该如何处理这事
I wanna know what we're going to do about this.
我认为圣地亚哥应该马上调离基地
I think Santiago should be transferred off the base immediately.
他那样差劲吗？
He's that bad, huh?
除此之外，信的内容一传出去…
Not only that. But word of this letter is bound to get out.
他可就有得受了
He's gonna get his ass whipped.
调走圣地亚哥
Hmm. Transfer Santiago.
好吧，我相信你是对的
Yes. I'm sure you're right.
我相信就该这么办
I'm sure that's the thing to do.
等等，我有个更好的主意
Wait. I've got a better idea.
我们把整个班都调离基地
Let's transfer the whole squad off the base.
我们…接下来考虑，Ｗ
Let's... On second thought, Windward...
我们将整个Ｗ连都调离基地
Let's transfer the whole Windward Division off the base.
约翰，到外边去把弟兄们都从边境带走
John, go on out there and get those boys down off the fence.
他们正在收拾行李，汤姆
They're packing their bags. Tom.
长官 给我接总统
Sir. Get me the president on the phone.
我们要放弃古巴的军事基地
We're surrendering our position in Cuba.
是，长官 等等，汤姆
Yes, sir. Wait a minute, Tom.
先不要接总统
Don't get the president just yet.
也许我们该考虑一下
Maybe we should consider this for a second.
出去吧，汤姆 是，长官
Dismissed, Tom. Yes, sir.
也许…我刚才是胡说八道
Maybe... and I'm just spit-balling here...
也许作为长官我们有责任训练圣地亚哥
Maybe we have a responsibility as officers to train Santiago.
也许作为长官我们有责任为国家…
Maybe we as officers have a responsibility to this country...
看着那些肩负国家安全重任的人…
to see that the men and women charged with its security...
受到专业的训练
are trained professionals.
没错，我确信在什么地方看到过这些话
Yes, I'm certain that I read that somewhere once.
我现在想的是，马金森中校…
And now I'm thinking, Colonel Markinson...
你提议调走圣地亚哥…
that your suggestion of transferring Santiago...
痛快固然是痛快…
while expeditious and certainly painless...
但恐怕不是美国人处理事情的方式
might not be, in a manner of speaking... the American way.
圣地亚哥必须留在这
Santiago stays where he is.
我们要训练这个小伙子
We're gonna train the lad.
约翰，由你负责
John, you're in charge.
如果圣地亚哥下次的训练和实习报告 还达不到四-六-四-六的话
Santiago doesn't make 4-6-4-6... on his next proficiency and conduct report...
我唯你是问
I'm going to blame you.
我会毙了你 是，长官
Then I'm going to kill you. Yes, sir.
我认为这是个错误，上校
I think that's a mistake, Colonel.
马修，我想我有些话要和你私下聊聊
Matthew, I think I will have that word in private with you now.
约翰，就这样吧 我们午饭时在军官俱乐部碰头…
John, that's all. Why don't we meet at the "O" club and have lunch...
讨论怎样训练小威廉
and we'll talk about the training of young William?
我很乐意听听您的建议，长官
I'd be delighted to hear any suggestions that you might have, sir.
出去吧 是，长官
Dismissed. Yes, sir.
马修，请坐下
Matthew, sit down. Please.
你觉得肯德瑞克怎么样？
What doyou think of Kendrick?
我对他的看法毫无
My opinion of him has nothing to do...
就我个人而言我觉得他不太靠得住…
I think he's pretty much of a weasel myself...
但他是个很不错的军官
but he's an awfully good officer.
我们最终的目的 就是要训练一支最好的海军陆战队
And in the end, we see eye-to-eye on the best way to run a Marine Corps unit.
保家卫国是我们份内的事，马修
We're in the business of saving lives, Matthew.
这是我们该认真对待的职责
That is a responsibility that we have to take pretty seriously.
我相信对于这样一名 不称职的海军陆战队员…
And I believe that taking a Marine who is not quite up to the job...
把他送到其他单位…
and shipping him off to another assignment...
是拿生命当儿戏
puts lives in danger.
坐下，马修
Sit down, Matthew.
想想过去吧
We go back a while.
我们一同上军校，一同接受任命
We went to the Academy together. We were commissioned together.
一同经历过越战
We did our tours in Vietnam together.
只不过我得到的一系列提升…
But I've been promoted up through the chain...
比起你来要运气好一些
with greater speed and success than you have.
现在，如果是因为这个…
Now, if that's a source of tension...
令你感到难堪…
or embarrassment foryou...
我不会太在意
I don't give a shit.
我们的职责性命攸关，马金森中校
We're in the business of saving lives, Lieutenant Colonel Markinson.
永远别在其他军官面前质疑我的命令
Don't ever question my orders in front of another officer.
所有材料都准备好了
All the paperwork's in order.
过去吧 是，长官
Step over there. Yes, sir.
哈罗德，这就是华盛顿特区？
Hal, is this Washington, D. C?
对，我们走吧
All right. Let's move.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
这一击能拿满分 打扰一下
Got all of that one. Excuse me.
我想和你谈谈道森和多尼的事
I wanted to talk to you about Corporal Dawson and Private Downey.
什么？ 道森和多尼
Say again? Dawson and Downey.
这些名字听起来和我有点关系
Those names sound like they should mean something to me...
道森，多尼…你的当事人
Dawson, Downey... your clients.
古巴的事，对了，道森和多尼，没错
The Cuba thing. Yes! Dawson and Downey. Right.
我又做错了什么吗？
I've done something wrong again, haven't I?
我只是奇怪那两个人一早就被关押的同时 他们的律师却在打球
I was just wondering why two guys have been locked up... since this morning while their lawyer's outside hitting a ball.
我们需要训练
We need the practice.
这并不好笑
That wasn't funny.
有一点点好笑
It was a little funny.
如果我向你的上司建议另外指派律师 会不会令你感到羞辱？
Would you be very insulted if I recommended to your supervisor... that he assign different counsel?
理由呢？ 我认为你不适合办理此案
Why? I don't think you're fit to handle it.
你根本不了解我 一般来说，总得花些时间…
You don't even know me. Ordinarily, it takes someone hours...
来了解我适不适合作辩护律师
to discover I'm not fit to handle a defense.
得了吧，这未免太可笑了
Oh, come on. That was damn funny.
你错了
You're wrong.
我了解你
I do know you.
丹尼・艾勒斯塔・凯菲 一九六四年六月八日生于…
Daniel Alistair Kaffee, born June 8, 1964...
波士顿仁爱医院
at Boston Mercy Hospital.
你父亲莱昂内尔・凯菲…
Your father's Lionel Kaffee...
曾担任海军军法检察官及美国司法部长
former Navy judge advocate and attorney general of the United States.
一九八五年去世
Died 1985.
你上过哈佛法学院，毕业后加入海军…
You went to Harvard law. Then you joined the Navy...
也许这是出于你父亲的要求
probably because that's what your father wanted you to do.
所以现在你只想在海军军法署混上三年
And now you're just treading water for three years in the JAG Corps.
混到退役找一份真正的工作
Just laying low till you can get out and get a real job.
如果是这样的话也无可厚非 我不会告诉任何人
If that's the situation, that's fine. I won't tell anyone.
但我认为如果象求快，耍小聪明的 波斯商贩那样来对待本案…
But it's my feeling that if this case is handled in the same... fast-food, slick-ass, Persian bazaar manner...
用你应付其他案子的那一套…
with which you seem to handle everything else...
就会漏掉一些东西
then something's gonna get missed.
如果道森和多尼因为他们的律师…
And I wouldn't be doing my job if I allowed Dawson and Downey...
预先就盘算不尽全力而使他们…
to spend any more time in prison than absolutely necessary...
多受哪怕一天的牢狱之灾，就是我的失职
because their attorney had predetermined the path of least resistance.
真令我兴奋，少校
I'm sexually aroused, Commander.
我不相信他们会杀人
I don't think your clients murdered anyone.
理由根据呢？
What are you basing this on?
没有动机
There was no intent.
医检报告说圣地亚哥死于窒息…
The doctor's report says Santiago died of asphyxiation...
是因为急性乳酸中毒…
brought on by acute lactic acidosis...
而这种症状很容易让人联想到是人为的
and that the nature of the acidosis strongly suggests poison.
我不知道这表示什么，但听起来相当不妙
I don't know what any of that means, but it sounds pretty bad.
圣地亚哥是死于凌晨一点
Santiago died at 1:00 a.m.
三点时医生还无法确定死因
At 3:00, the doctor wasn't able to determine the cause of death.
两小时后，他说是死于中毒
Two hours later, he said it was poison.
哦，我现在懂你的意思了
Oh, now I see what you're saying.
肯定是图书馆的普拉姆教授 用烛台打死了他
It had to be Professor Plum in the library with a candlestick.
我去和你的上司谈好了 行啊
I'm gonna talk to your supervisor. Okay.
直接去宾州林荫大道
Go straight up Pennsylvania Avenue.
找一幢有柱子的白色宫殿
It's the big white house with the pillars in front.
谢了 我觉得你的运气不会太好
Thank you. I don't think you'll have much luck.
我是由师部任命的
I was assigned by Division.
那儿有人认为我是个很不错的律师
Somebody over there thinks I'm a pretty good lawyer.
我对你的专注和热情表示敬佩…
So while I appreciate your interest and admire your enthusiasm...
但我认为我自己能处理好这事
I think I can handle things myself.
知道什么是“红色条规”吗？
You know what a Code Red is?
真遗憾
What a pity.
早，长官 早
Morning, sir. Morning.
长官到，立正
Officer on deck!
长官，哈罗德・道森准下士，长官
Sir, Lance Corporal Harold W. Dawson, sir!
隶属Ｗ步兵警卫连二Ｂ排
Rifle Security Company Windward, Second Platoon Bravo.
曾经违纪并且 不能和队友好好相处的哈罗德？
Someone hasn't been working and playing well with others, Harold.
长官，是的，长官
Sir, yes, sir!
长官，一等兵劳登・多尼，长官
Sir, P.F.C. Louden Downey, sir!
我是丹尼・凯菲，这是山姆・温伯格
I'm Daniel Kaffee. This is Sam Weinberg.
坐吧
Sit down.
这是你的签名？ 是的，长官
This your signature? Yes, sir.
用不着叫我长官，这是你的签名吗？
You don't have to call me "sir." Is this your signature?
长官，是的，长官
Sir, yes, sir.
完全没必要一句话叫两次长官
You certainly don't need to do it twice in one sentence.
什么是“红色条规”？ 是一种训诫条规
What's a Code Red? It is a disciplinary engagement.
表示什么？
What's that mean?
如果有陆战队员掉队 就可以用来帮助这个队员跟上队伍
A Marine falls out of line, it's up to the men in his unit to get him on track.
“红色条规”具体是什么花样？ 长官？
What's a garden variety Code Red? Sir?
哈罗德，你这么叫会让我 忍不住回头看是不是我爸爸来了
Harold, you say, "sir," and I turn around and look for my father.
叫我丹尼，凯菲都行
Danny, Daniel, Kaffee.
说明白点 “红色条规”大概是什么意思？
Garden variety. Typical. What's basic Code Red?
长官，比如有队员拒绝按规定洗澡…
Sir, a Marine refuses to bathe on a regular basis...
队友就会给他洗个“军用澡”
the men in his squad will give him a G.I. Shower.
怎么个洗法？
What's that?
用刷子，钢丝刷
Scrub brushes, Brillo pads, steel wool.
太妙了
Beautiful.
圣地亚哥接受的也是“红色条规”吗？
Was the attack on Santiago a Code Red?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
他从不说话吗？
Does he ever talk?
长官，一等兵多尼会回答你的所有问题
Sir, P.F.C. Downey will answer any direct questions you ask him.
非？
Swell.
多尼，你塞进圣地亚哥嘴里的抹布
Private Downey, the rag you stuffed in Santiago's mouth...
有没有毒？ 没有，长官
Was there poison on it? No, sir.
上光剂，松节油，防冻剂之类？
Silver polish, turpentine, antifreeze?
没有，长官，我们只是想给他剃头
No, sir. We were just gonna shave his head, sir.
突然之间
When all of the sudden...
我们看到他的嘴在流血…
We saw blood dripping down his mouth...
我们撕掉胶布，他满脸都是血，长官
and we pulled the tape off and there was blood all down his face, sir.
接着道森准下士就打电话叫了救护车
That's when Lance Corporal Dawson called the ambulance.
有人看到你打电话吗？
Did anyone see you call the ambulance?
没有，长官
No, sir.
救护车来时你在那吗？
Were you there when the ambulance got there?
是的，长官，这时我们已经被拘捕
Yes, sir. That's when we were taken under arrest.
八月二日夜间 你是否在边界向古巴境内开过枪？
The night of August 2, did you fire a shot across the fenceline into Cuba?
是的，长官 为什么？
Yes, sir. Why?
我的对象在动手，长官 对象？
My mirror engaged, sir. His mirror?
每个美军岗哨都有一个对应的古巴岗哨 称为“对象”
Every American sentry post has a Cuban counterpart, called "mirrors."
下士的意思是他的对象想向他开枪
Lance Corporal's claiming that his mirror was about to fire at him.
圣地亚哥写信给海军调查处…
Santiago's letter to the N.I. S...
说你违纪开枪
said you fired illegally.
他说那个人，那个对象
He's saying that the guy, the mirror...
决没有任何行动
He never made a move.
你明白我在说什么吗？
You see what I'm getting at?
既然圣地亚哥和你没有私怨 为何对他执行“红色条规”？
If Santiago didn't have anything on you, then why did you give him a Code Red?
因为他越级上报，长官
'Cause he broke the chain of command, sir.
什么？ 他撇开了自己的单位，长官
He what? He went outside of his unit, sir.
如果他有问题，应该先向我报告，长官
If he had a problem, he should have spoken to me, sir.
然后才是中士，指挥官 好了好了
Then his sergeant, then commander... Yeah. All right.
你袭击他时是否意图杀死他？
Did you assault Santiago with the intent of killing him?
没有，长官 意图何在？
No, sir. What was your intent?
教训他，长官 教训他什么？
To train him, sir. Train him to do what?
考虑个人之前先考虑集体…要尊重秩序
Train him to think of his unit before himself... to respect the code.
什么秩序？
What's the code?
分队，军团，上帝，国家
Unit, Corps, God, Country.
能再说一次吗？
I beg your pardon?
依次为分队、军团、上帝、国家，长官
Unit, Corps, God, Country, sir.
美国政府…
The government of the United States...
要指控你俩谋杀…
wants to charge you two with murder...
你想让我对起诉人说什么 分队，军团，上帝，国家吗？
and you want me to go to the prosecutor... with "Unit, Corps, God, Country"?
这是我们的规矩，长官
That's our code, sir.
你们的规矩
It's your code.
我们还会来
We'll be back.
有什么需要吗？ 书，纸张，香烟，火腿三明治？
You guys need anything... books, papers, cigarettes, ham sandwich?
长官，不用，谢谢，长官
Sir, no, thank you, sir.
哈罗德，我觉得你最好开始明白一件事
Harold, I think there's a concept you better start warming up to.
长官？
Sir?
我是你们唯一的朋友
I'm the only friend you've got.
丹尼・凯菲
Daniel Kaffee
微笑的杰克・罗斯
Smiling Jack Ross.
欢迎你的加入 是吗？
Welcome to the big time. You think so?
为道森和多尼着想 但愿你的专业水平高于垒球水平
Let's hope, for Dawson and Downey, you practice law better than play softball.
真为他俩遗憾 我没有什么能比垒球更擅长
Unfortunately for those two, I don't do anything better than play softball.
我走了，简奈儿 再见
I'm out of here, Janelle. Bye.
等我从古巴回来再见 代我向卡斯特罗问好
See you when I get back from Cuba. Say hi to Castro for me.
没问题，有何见教？
Will do. What are we looking at?
他们认罪 就网开一面只告他们共谋及行为不当
They plead guilty, we drop the conspiracy and conduct unbecoming.
二十年，十年后就能回家 我想要十二年
Twentyyears. They're home in half. I want 12.
办不到 他们叫了救护车
Can't do it. They called the ambulance.
我不在乎他们叫过谁，总之他们杀了人
I don't care if they called the Avon lady. They killed a Marine.
那块抹布化验过了 法医和化验报告都说未必如此
The rag was tested for poison. The autopsy, lab reports. They say the same thing: Maybe, maybe not.
关达那摩湾海军医院的内科主任…
Chief of Internal Medicine at the Guantanamo Bay Naval Hospital...
说他可以肯定
says he's sure.
你知道“红色条规”吗？
What do you know about Code Reds?
哦，老天
Oh, man.
这算私人谈话吧？ 说说看
We off the record? Tell me.
就依你的，判十二年
I'm gonna give you the 12 years.
不过你在明天给自己惹麻烦之前该知道…
Before you go getting yourself into trouble tomorrow, you should know...
排长乔纳森・肯德瑞克上尉…
the platoon commander, Lieutenant Jonathan Kendrick...
召集手下开过会并且特地…
held a meeting with the men and specifically...
告诉他们别碰圣地亚哥
told them not to touch Santiago.
我们明晚还打篮球吗？ 算是成交了？
We still playing hoops tomorrow night? Do we have a deal?
等我回来再说
I'll talk toyou when I get back.
你好 找到谁替换我了吗？
Hi there. Any luck getting me replaced?
是不是部里所有人都是你的酒友或球友？
Is there anyone in this command you don't either drink or play ball with?
少校 听着，我是来讲和的
Commander... Listen. I came to make peace.
我承认之前对你有误会 怎么样？可以做朋友吗？
Got off on the wrong foot. What do you say? Friends?
我照多尼的要求给他带了些漫画
I brought Downey some comic books he was asking for.
这孩子根本不明白自己的处境
The kid, Kaffee, I swear he doesn't know where he is.
甚至不知为何被捕 少校
Doesn't even know why he's arrested. Commander.
可以叫我乔安妮 乔安妮
You can call me Joanne. Joanne.
乔也可以 好的
Or Jo. Yes.
乔，如果你再私自和我的当事人交谈…
Jo, if you ever speak to a client of mine again without my permission...
我就把你排除在外
I'll have you disbarred.
行吗，朋友？ 有人授权给我
Friends? I had authorization.
谁？ 多尼最亲的亲人
From where? Downey's closest living relative.
詹妮・米勒，他的姨妈
Ginny Miller. His aunt on his mother's side.
詹妮・米勒授权给了你？
You got authorization from Aunt Ginny?
我照你的要求给她打了电话
I gave her a call like you asked.
很不错的女人，我们聊了将近一小时
Very nice woman. We spoke for about an hour.
詹妮・米勒授权给了你
You got authorization from Aunt Ginny.
我完全有这个权利
Perfectly within my province.
她有车库吗？我们可以在那庭审
Does Aunt Ginny have a barn? We could hold the trial there.
我懂缝纫，没准能给他叔叔缝件法官制服
I can sew the costumes. Maybe his Uncle Goober can be the judge.
我明天和你一起去古巴
I'm going to Cuba with you tomorrow.
看来好戏还在后头
And the hits just keep on coming.
过得怎么样，卢瑟？ 多活一天算一天，中尉
How's it going, Luther? Another day, another dollar, captain.
看来你是听天由命了 爱怎么着怎么着吧
You gotta play them as they lay. What goes around comes around.
惹不起就投降好了 至少我的身体还行
Can't beatthem, joingem. At least I got my health.
这比什么都实在，明天见，卢瑟
Well, then you got everything. See you tomorrow, Luther.
我可会躲着你
Not if I seeyou first.
别忘了莎莉回来时给我作证
Now don't forget. When Sally gets back, you're my witness.
孩子说话了，我女儿说话了
The baby spoke. My daughter said a word.
我可不能肯定她那是在说话
Your daughter made a sound, Sam. I'm not sure it was a word.
得了吧，那肯定是在说话
Come on, now. It was definitely a word.
你明明听到她在指着我说“爸爸”
You heard her. The girl sat here, pointed and said, "Pa."
没错，她就是说“爸爸”
She did. She said, "Pa."
可她指的是邮筒，山姆
She was pointing at a mailbox, Sam.
没错，等于是说：“爸爸，看，邮筒”
That's right, pointing as if to say, "Pa, look. A mailbox."
杰克・罗斯今天找过我 他同意只判十二年
Jack Ross came to see me today. He offered me the 12 years.
正是你想要的不是吗？ 我知道
Oh, that's what you wanted, right? I know, I know.
我是说，我觉得应该接受，应该接受
I mean, I guess I'll take it. I'll take it.
那么，只用了四十五秒就说定了
So... It took about 45 seconds.
没费多大力气
He barely put up a fight.
丹尼，接受吧，这是份大礼
Danny, take the 12 years. It's a gift.
你不相信他们的供词对吧？
You don't believe their story, do you?
你觉得他们该在牢里过下半辈子
You think they ought to go to jail for the rest of their lives.
我相信他们说的每句话…
I believe every word of their story...
也认为他们该在牢里过下半辈子
and I think they ought to go to jail for the rest oftheir lives.
明天见 好的
See you tomorrow. Okay.
别忘了穿白色制服，那边很热
Don't forget to wear the whites. Very hot down there.
我不喜欢白色制服
I don't like the whites.
没人喜欢，但我们要去古巴
Nobody likes the whites, but we're going to Cuba.
有没有茶苯海明？ 是用来降温的吗？
You got Dramamine? Dramamine keeps you cool?
不，是用来防止呕吐的 坐飞机会让你感到不舒服
No, Dramamine keeps you from throwing up. You get sick when you fly.
我不舒服是因为担心飞机撞到山上
I get sick when I fly because I'm afraid of crashing into a large mountain.
恐怕茶苯海明没什么用
I don't think Dramaminewill help.
我有些牛至，听说很管用
I got some oregano. I hear that works pretty good.
罗斯提到的一件怪事让我改变了想法
You know, Ross said the strangest thing to me right before I left.
他说排长乔纳森・肯德瑞克上尉…
He said the platoon commander Lieutenant Jonathan Kendrick...
召集手下开会告诉他们别碰圣地亚哥
had a meeting with the men and told them not to touch Santiago.
那么？
So?
我从没提过这人，根本不知道他是谁
I never mentioned Kendrick. I don't even know who he is.
管他怎么回事，明天见
Ah, what the hell. I'll see you tomorrow.
两位中尉，盖洛维少校
Lieutenants Kaffee and Weinberg, Commander Galloway.
我是巴恩斯下士，是来送你们去基地的
I'm Corporal Barnes. I'm to escort you to the windward side of the base.
谢谢 我这有几件迷彩服
Thank you. I got some camouflage jackets here.
我建议你们都穿上 迷彩服？
I suggest you both put them on. Camouflage jackets?
是的，长官，我们一路上离边境相当近
Yes, sir. We'll be riding pretty close to the fenceline.
古巴人看到穿白制服的军官…
The Cubans see an officer wearing white...
有可能认为是重要人物而开枪
they think it might be someone they want to take a shot at.
你出的好主意，山姆
Good call, Sam.
很快就到渡口，要不了多久
We'll just hop on the ferry. We'll be there in no time.
等等，还得坐船吗？ 是的，长官
Wait. We gotta take a boat? Yes, sir.
要到海湾的另一侧 没人提过要坐船
To get to the other side of the bay. Nobody said anything about a boat.
有问题吗，长官？ 不，没问题
Is there a problem, sir? No, no problem.
只是讨厌坐船而已
Just not crazy about boats.
老天，凯菲 你可是海军，却因为坐船而感到害怕
Jesus Christ, Kaffee, you're in the Navy, for crying out loud.
没人会对坐船太感兴趣 是的，长官
Nobody likes her very much. Yes, sir!
我是内森・杰赛普，请进
Nathan Jessup. Come on in.
谢谢，长官，我是丹尼・凯菲 道森和多尼的律师
Thank you, sir. Daniel Kaffee. I'm the attorney for Dawson and Downey.
这是乔安妮・盖洛维少校
This is Lieutenant Commander Joanne Galloway.
幸会，少校 她负责监督评估，长官
Pleasure meeting you, Commander. Observing and evaluating, sir.
山姆・温伯格中尉，我的助手
Lieutenant Sam Weinberg. He'll be assisting.
长官 这是我的助手，马金森中校…
Sir. This is my X.O., Colonel Markinson...
和排长肯德瑞克上尉
and platoon leader Lieutenant Kendrick.
是我让他们来的，请坐
I've asked them to join us. Sit down, please.
凯菲中尉 马金森中校
Lieutenant Kaffee. Colonel Markinson.
我曾有幸见过你父亲一面
I had the pleasure of meeting your father once.
我当时才十多岁，他到学校去演讲
I was a teenager. He spoke at my high school.
莱昂纳尔・凯菲？
Lionel Kaffee?
是的，长官 你们知道吗？
Yes, sir. Well, what do you know?
约翰，他父亲曾在你老家得罪过很多人
John, this man's dad once made a lot of enemies down in your neck of the woods.
杰斐逊和麦迪逊地区学校打官司
Jefferson v. Madison County School District.
当地人反对一个黑人女孩到白人学校上学
Folks down there said a black girl couldn't go to an all-white school.
莱昂纳尔・凯菲说 “我们就等着瞧好了”
Lionel Kaffee said, "Well, we'll just see about that."
你父亲怎么样，丹尼？
How the hell is your dad, Danny?
他七年前去世了，长官
He passed away seven years ago, sir.
千万别以为我是故意这么问
Don't I feel like the fucking asshole.
绝对不会
Not at all.
有什么需要我们效劳的，丹尼？
Well, what can we do for you, Danny?
没什么，长官
Uh, not much, sir.
说起来纯粹只是例行公事而已
This is really a formality more than anything else.
军法署署长要求我们面见所有相关证人
JAG Corps insists that we interview all the relevant witnesses.
署长有权这样要求
The JAG Corps can be demanding that way.
约翰会带你们去见想见的人
John will take you out and show you what you want to see.
之后我们可以一起吃午饭
After that we can all hook up for lunch.
怎么样？ 好的，长官
How does that sound? Good. Fine, sir.
那天下午你召集部下开过会是吗？
I understand you had a meeting with your men that afternoon.
是的，没错 都说了些什么？
Yes, I did. What did you guys talk about?
我告诉他们我们中间有个告密者…
I told the men that we had an informer among us...
不管大家有多想惩罚他…
and that despite any desire they might have to seek retribution...
总之不得伤害一等兵圣地亚哥
Private Santiago was not to be harmed in anyway.
什么时候开的会？
16:00 What time was that meeting? 16:00.
就是四点
That's 4:00.
山姆，应该找人把这些送交他的父母
Sam, we should make sure somebody gets this to his parents.
我们不再需要这些了 是啊
We don't need it anymore. Right.
肯德瑞克上尉，能叫你约翰吗？
Lieutenant Kendrick, may I call you John?
不，不行
No, you may not.
我是不是冒犯了你？
Have I done something to offend you?
不，我喜欢你们海军
No, I like all you Navy boys.
每次我们去什么地方打仗 你们总会送我们一程
Every time we gotta go someplace to fight, you fellas always give us a ride.
肯德瑞克上尉 你认为圣地亚哥是死于谋杀吗？
Lieutenant Kendrick, do you think Santiago was murdered?
少校，我信奉主和他的儿子耶稣
Commander, I believe in God and His Son Jesus Christ.
所以我只能说
And because I do, I can say this:
一等兵圣地亚哥死了，这是个悲剧
Private Santiago is dead, and that is a tragedy.
但他的死是因为不守规矩
But he is dead because he had no code.
他的死是因为他对主不敬 而上帝觉察到了
He is dead because he had no honor, and God was watching.
你同意这种观点吗？
How do you feel about that theory?
有道理，我们走吧
Sounds good. Let's move on.
你的计划是来此调查…
Are you planning on doing any investigating...
还是仅仅来旅游？
or are you just gonna take the guided tour?
我有我的处理方式
I'm pacing myself.
他们来来回回跑了三个钟头…
They were running around for three hours...
想找些白色的东西用来当白旗
Iooking for anything white they could wave in the air.
有些人向一个有线新闻网的人投了降
Some of these people surrendered to a crew from CNN.
我总是说，无遮无掩 却战胜了一支装甲部队
Well, walk softly and carry an armored tank division, I always say.
味道很好，谢谢 是我的荣幸，长官
That was delicious. Thank you. My pleasure, sir.
上校，我想问您几个关于九月六日的问题
Colonel, I do have to ask you a couple of questions about September 6.
尽管问
Shoot.
早上六点，您曾接触过 一个海军调查处的官员…
On the morning of the sixth, you were contacted by an N.I.S. Agent...
他说圣地亚哥曾向他透露 一起边界违规开枪事件
who said that Santiago tipped him off to an illegal fenceline shooting.
是的 圣地亚哥是以此…
Yes. Santiago would reveal the person...
作为调动的交换条件 是的
in exchange for a transfer. Yes.
如果您觉得我漏掉了什么细节…
If you feel there are any details that I'm missing...
您可以直接了当地说出来
you should feel free to speak up.
谢谢
Thank you.
然后您将马金森中校 和肯德瑞克上尉叫到了您的办公室
Now, at this point you called Lieutenant Colonel Markinson... and Lieutenant Kendrick into your office.
是这样吗？ 是的
Is that right? Yes.
结果呢？
What happened?
我们都同意 为了圣地亚哥的安全应该将他调离基地
We agreed that, for his own safety, Santiago should be transferred off base.
圣地亚哥已被安排调离基地？
Santiago was set to be transferred.
搭乘第二天凌晨六点 第一趟飞往美国的航班
On the first available flight to the States... 0600 the next morning.
从结果来看，五个小时太长了
Five hours too late, as it turned out.
好了，就到这吧，非常感谢各位
All right. That's all I have. Thanks very much for your time.
下士在车上等着，他会送你们回机场
Corporal's waiting with the Jeep. He'll take you back to the flight line.
谢谢，长官 等等，我还有些问题
Thank you, sir. Wait. I've got some questions.
不，别问了 不，我要问
No, you don't. Yes, I do.
不，别问了 圣地亚哥死的那天早上…
No, you don't. On the morning that Santiago died...
三点到五点之间您有没有见过斯通医生？
did you meet with Dr. Stone between 3:00 and 5:00?
我的一名步下死了，我当然要见医生
Of course I met with the doctor. One of my men was dead.
懂了吧？人都死了，走吧
See? The man was dead. Let's go.
我想知道您是否听说过“红色条规”
I'm just wondering if you've ever heard the term "Code Red."
我听说过，是的
I've heard the term, yes.
今年二月，您收到过一份警诫备忘录…
This past February, you received a cautionary memo...
是由大西洋舰队总司令签发的…
from the commander-in-chief of the Atlantic fleet...
警告军官 不得纵容现役军人私自实施处罚
warning that the practice of enlisted men... disciplining their own wasn't to be condoned by officers.
我得提醒你写备忘录的人…
Well, I submit to you that whoever wrote that memo...
绝对不用面对…
has never faced the working end...
古巴人手上的苏制ＡＫ４７自动步枪
of a Soviet-made Cuban AK-47 assault rifle.
不过，对于总司令的指示…
However, the directive having come from the commander...
我给予了应有的关注
I gave it its due attention.
你的重点是什么，乔？ 她没有重点
What is your point, Jo? She has no point.
没有重点是她迷人之处
She often has no point. It's part of her charm.
我们走了，谢谢 我认为这里仍然存在“红色条规”
We're out of here. Thank you. I think Code Reds still go on here.
是不是这样？ 乔，他用不着回答这些
Do Code Reds still happen here? Jo, he doesn't need to answer that.
不，他必须回答 不，他真的不用
Yes, he does. No, he really doesn't.
他必须回答
Yeah, he really does.
真是抓住了我的要害
You know, it just hit me.
她军衔比你高吧，丹尼？
She outranks you, Danny.
是的，长官 我要告诉你一件事
Yes, sir. I wanna tell you something.
听好了，因为我很在意这事
And listen up,'cause I really mean this.
你是世上最幸运的男人
You're the luckiest man in the world.
相信我，各位…世上没有什么事情
There is nothing on this earth sexier... believe me, gentlemen...
比你一大早就得给一个女人敬礼更性感
than a woman that you have to salute in the morning.
把她们全都提升，因为事实上
Promote them all, I say,'cause this is true:
如果没有上级军官为你口交…
If you haven't gotten a blow job from a superior officer...
那你就错过了生活中最美妙的东西
well, you're just letting the best in life pass you by.
上校，“红色条规”仍被军官
Colonel, the practice of Code Reds is still condoned by officers...
我的问题在于我是个上校 所以我得去洗个冷水澡…
My problem is that I'm a colonel, so I'll go on taking cold showers...
直到选出一位女总统
until they elect some gal president.
我要你回答我的问题，长官
I need an answer to my question, sir.
注意你的语气，少校
Take caution in your tone, Commander.
我是个平和的人 但这该死的高温让我完全失去了理智
I'm a fair guy, but this fucking heat is making me absolutely crazy.
你问“红色条规”？在档案上…
You wanna ask me about Code Reds? On the record...
我是禁止实施的…
I tell you I discourage the practice...
和总司令的指示一致
in accordance with the commander's directive.
但撇开档案，告诉你 是军团内部训练很重要的一部分
Off the record, I tell you it is an invaluable part... of close-infantry training.
只要事情不是发生在我眼皮底下 就顺其自然
And if it happens to go on without my knowledge, so be it.
我以我的方式来管理我的部下
I run my unit how I run my unit.
你想调查我 尽管看看你有多大的机会好了
You wanna investigate me, roll the dice and take your chances.
我吃早餐时三百码外 有四千名训练有素的古巴人想干掉我
I eat breakfast 300 yards from 4,000 Cubans who are trained to kill me.
所以别以为你可以跑到这来…
So don't think for one second that you can come down here...
耀武扬威…
flash a badge...
吓唬我
and make me nervous.
我们走吧
Let's go.
上校，我需要一份圣地亚哥调令的复印件
Colonel, I'll just need a copy of Santiago's transfer order.
什么？
What's that?
圣地亚哥的调令，你们应该有这一类档案
Santiago's transfer order. You guys have paperwork on that kind of thing.
我需要一份存档
I just need it for the file.
存档 是的
For the file. Yeah.
你当然可以复印一份调令用来存档
Of course you can have a copy of the transfer order for the file.
我会尽力协助你们 谢谢
I'm here to help in anyway I can. Thank you.
你相不相信我会尽我所能协助你？
You believe that, don't you, Danny, that I'm here to help you in anyway I can?
当然
Of course.
去机场时下士会送你们去人事部门…
Corporal will take you by personnel on your way out to the flight line...
你可以复印你想要的所有调令
and you can have all the transfer orders that you want.
走吧 但你们得对我客气点
Let's go. But you have to ask me nicely.
什么？
I beg your pardon?
你得对我客气点
You have to ask me nicely.
知道吗，丹尼，枪林弹雨流血我都能应付
You see, Danny, I can deal with the bullets and the bombs and the blood.
我不需要金钱，不需要奖章
I don't want money, and I don't want medals.
我要的是穿着娘娘腔的白色制服 的你站在那…
What I do want is for you to stand there in that faggoty white uniform...
用你那哈佛练出来的嘴 给我一点该死的尊重
and with your Harvard mouth extend me some fucking courtesy.
你得对我客气点
You gotta ask me nicely.
杰赛普上校，如果不太麻烦的话…
Colonel Jessup, if it's not too much trouble...
我想要一份调令的复印件，长官
I'd like a copy of the transfer order, sir.
没问题
No problem.
第七局，“圣地亚哥”领先 “勇士”试图扳平
In the seventh. San Diego leads. Braves try to come back.
跑垒员别急
Runners don't go.
有力的一击，右外野手，好戏上演了
Hard drive, right field. We're gonna have a tied ball game.
成功了，现在的比分是十比十
It's on its way, and it is now 10 to 10.
真是难以置信
And I don't believe it.
谁？ 是我
Who is it? It's me.
我真想你 我在这自言自语都快三个钟头了
I really missed you. I was just saying to myself it's been almost three hours.
马金森失踪了 什么？
Markinson's disappeared. What?
马金森中校擅离职守
Colonel Markinson's gone U. A... unauthorized absence.
知道了，什么时候？
I know what it means. When?
今天下午，我们离开之后
This afternoon. Sometime after we left.
我明早去找他 我找过了
I'll try to find him in the morning. I've already tried.
找过了？
You tried?
乔安，你几乎够得上教科书上定义的…
Joanne, you're coming dangerously close to the textbook definition...
妨碍政府调查的罪名了
of interfering with a government investigation.
我是劳登・多尼的律师
I'm Louden Downey's attorney.
詹妮姨妈说她似乎已和我相交多年
Aunt Ginny. She says she feels like she's known me for years.
所以我建议由我直接介入本案 可以显得更亲近
So I suggested that she might feel more comfortable... if I were directly involved with the case.
一小时前她得到了劳登的签名同意
She had Louden sign the papers about an hour ago.
我想你对此期望过高了…
I suppose it's way too much to hope...
你讨好她就会妨碍我
that you're making this up just to bother me.
别担心，我并不想自作主张
Don't worry. I'm not gonna make a motion for separation.
你还是首席辩护 好极了
You're still lead counsel. Splendid.
我猜你也同意 是肯德瑞克授意的“红色条规”
I think Kendrick ordered the Code Red, and so do you.
我们走吧
Let's go.
长官到，立正
Officer on deck!
是肯德瑞克的命令吗？ 长官？
Did Kendrick order the Code Red? Sir?
别好象我在问你是否打扫过厕所似的
Don't say "Sir" like I just asked you if you cleaned the latrine.
是不是上尉命令你们…
You heard what I said. Did Lieutenant Kendrick order you guys...
对圣地亚哥实施“红色条规”？
to give Santiago a Code Red?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
是他吗？ 是的，长官
Did he? Yes, sir.
介不介意说说为什么以前不告诉我？
You mind telling me why you never mentioned this before?
你没问过 这可不会让我对你有什么好印象
You didn't ask. That won't win you a place in my heart.
你在牢里蹲多久我照样拿薪水
I get paid no matter how much time you spend in jail.
是的，长官，我知道，长官
Yes, sir. I know you do, sir.
去你的，哈罗德 好了
Fuck you, Harold! All right.
冷静点
At ease.
我们来说说清楚 活见鬼
Let's sort this thing out. Shit!
九月六日下午四点排里开过一个会
There was a platoon meeting on September 6 at 4:00 in the afternoon.
肯德瑞克上尉说他严令…
Lieutenant Kendrick says that he gave strict instructions...
不许碰圣地亚哥
that nothing was to happen to Santiago.
是真的吗？
Now, is this true?
你们要实话实话
I want you to speak freely.
夫人，是真的…
Ma'am, that's correct...
但之后我们就解散各自回房了
but then he dismissed the platoon and we all went to our rooms.
后来怎么样？
And what happened then?
肯德瑞克上尉去了我们的房间
Lieutenant Kendrick came to our room, ma'am.
几点？
When?
大约散会五分钟之后 长官，四点二十左右
About five minutes after the meeting broke, sir. About 1620.
然后呢？
And what happened then?
肯德瑞克上尉命令我们 对圣地亚哥执行“红色条规”
Lieutenant Kendrick ordered us to give Santiago a Code Red.
杰克
Jack!
等等
Hang on.
他们是奉命行事
They were given an order.
杰克，过来 马上回来
Jack, come on. Be right back.
你干什么，杰克？ 就回来
What are you doing, Jack? Be right back.
你知道这命令多久了？ 我不知道，这位是？
How long did you know about the order? I didn't. Who's this?
乔・盖洛维，多尼的律师 她很高兴认识你
That's Jo Galloway, Downey's lawyer. She's very pleased to meet you.
你想指责我什么？ 你知道这个命令多久了？
What exactly are you accusing me of? How long did you know about the order?
他不知道，如果知道却对我们隐瞒 就违反了职业守则第十四条
He didn't,'cause if he did and hadn't told us... he'd be violating about 14 articles of the Code of Ethics.
他就得担心…
He has enough to worry about...
当事人申请无罪…
God forbid our clients decide to plead not guilty...
并为他们是奉命行事作证
and testify for the record that they were given an order.
肯德瑞克曾明令部下不许碰圣地亚哥
Kendrick specifically told those men not to touch Santiago.
没错，然后他找了道森和多尼…
That's right. And then he went into Dawson and Downey's room...
明令他们执行“红色条规”
and specifically told them to give him a Code Red.
可他说…他在说谎 有证据吗？ 有被告作证
Kendrick said different. Have proof? He's lying. I have the defendants.
可我有二十三名 未被指控谋杀的陆战队员…
And I have 23 Marines who aren't accused of murder...
和一名受过四次嘉奖的上尉
and a lieutenant with four letters of commendation.
马金森为何擅离职守？ 无从查究
Why did Markinson go U. A? We'll never know.
你以为我不能传讯他吗？ 你能找到他再说
You don't think I could subpoena him? You can try, but you won't find him.
知道他二十六年军旅生涯的前十七年 是干什么吗？
You know what he did for the first 17 of his 26 years in the Corps?
反谍报工作，他消失了 再没有什么马金森了
Counterintelligence. Markinson's gone. There is no Markinson.
你看，丹尼
Look, Danny.
杰赛普很快就会提升
Jessup's star is on the rise.
师部会给我很大的余地…
Division will give me a lot of room on this one...
使他和部队免于难堪
to spare Jessup and the Corps any embarrassment.
多大的余地？
How much?
过失杀人，两年刑期 他们六个月后就能回家
Involuntary manslaughter, two years, they're home in six months.
没得商量，我们要上庭
No deal. We're going to court.
你们不会 为什么？
No, you're not. Why not?
因为你会输，丹尼明白这一点
'Cause you'll lose, and Danny knows it.
如果上了法庭我就要追查到底
If we do go to court, I'm gonna have to go all the way.
他们就得承担所有罪名…
They're gonna be charged with a whole truckload...
谋杀，共谋，行为不当
murder, conspiracy, conduct unbecoming.
在球场上他能赢我，可他知道…
Even though he's got me by the balls out here, Danny knows...
上了法庭他准会输
that in a courtroom, he loses this case.
丹尼是个天才横溢的律师
Danny is an awfully talented lawyer.
既然知道当事人六个月就能回家…
He's not about to see his clients go to jail for life...
就不会让他们蹲一辈子监狱
when he knows they can be home in six months.
协商到此为止
That's the end of this negotiation.
明早传讯时见
I'll see you tomorrow morning at the arraignment.
好了，情况是这样
All right. Here's the story.
政府提出以过失杀人罪判处两年刑期
The government's offering involuntary manslaughter, two years.
六个月后就能回家
Be home in six months.
哇，凯菲，你是世上最了不起的律师
Wow, Kaffee! You're the greatest lawyer in the world!
我们该怎么谢你呢？
Ooh, how can we ever thank you?
伙计们，你们听到我说什么了吧？
Fellas, you hear what I just said?
你们六个月后就能自由
You're going home in six months.
我恐怕不能接受，长官
I'm afraid we can't do that, sir.
接受什么？ 协商解决，长官
Do what? Make a deal, sir.
你说什么？
What are you talking about?
我们没做错什么，长官 我们只是恪守本份…
We did nothing wrong, sir. We did our job...
如果要因此而我会承受的
and if that has consequences, then I'll accept them.
但我不会承认有罪，长官
But I won't say that I'm guilty, sir.
是你…是不是她让你们这么说的？
Did you... Did she put you up to this?
这是我们的准则，长官 哦，令人激动
We have a code, sir. Oh, well, zip-a-dee-doo-dah!
你依你的准则申请无罪 就得在牢里过下半辈子
You and your code plead not guilty. You'll be in jail the rest of your life.
照我说的做六个月后就能回家
Do what I'm telling you, you'll be home in six months.
接受吧，哈罗德，六个月
Do it, Harold. Six months.
算不了什么，一个冰球赛季而已
It's nothing. It's a hockey season.
请允许我… 说吧
Permission to... Speak!
老天
Jesus!
我们以后怎么办，长官？ 什么以后？
What do we do then, sir? When?
六个月后，会被不荣誉解职是吧？长官
After six months, we'll be dishonorably discharged, right, sir?
有可能
Probably.
那时我们怎么办，长官？
Well, what do we do then, sir?
我们入伍是为了按一种明确的法规来生活
We joined the Marines because we wanted to live our lives by a certain code.
我们在部队感受到了
And we found it in the Corps.
现在你却要我们签字承认自己是不光彩的
Now you're asking us to sign a piece of paper that says we have no honor.
要我们承认不是陆战队员
You're asking us to say we're not Marines.
如果法庭判决我们犯了错…
If a court decides that what we did was wrong...
不管什么处罚我都接受
then I'll accept whatever punishment they give.
但我相信没做错，长官 我只是履行了自己的职责…
But I believe I was right, sir. I believe I did my job...
我不会为了六个月后能回家…
and I will not dishonor myself, my unit or the Corps...
而让自己，自己的单位和部队蒙羞…
so that I can go home in six months...
长官
sir.
少校，请让我和道森下士 单独聊一会行吗？
Commander, I'd like to talk to Lance Corporal Dawson alone for a minute.
中士
Sergeant.
我们去其他房间
We're gonna go to another room.
我们要去其他监禁室 好的，夫人
We'd like another holding room. All right, ma'am.
不会有问题 坐吧
It's gonna be okay. Sit down.
你很讨厌我是不是？
You don't like me very much, do you?
算了，不必回答，没关系
Forget it. Don't answer that. It doesn't matter.
知道吗…
You know...
多尼很尊敬你
Downey worships you.
你怎么做他就会怎么做
He's gonna do whatever you do.
你真的愿意因为一条准则 而让他受一辈子牢狱之灾吗，哈罗德？
Are you really gonna let this happen to him because of a code, Harold?
你觉得我们有错吗？ 问题不在这…
Do you think we were right? It doesn't matter...
你觉得我们有没有错？ 我觉得你们会输
Do you think we were right? I think you'd lose.
你是个懦夫
You're such a coward.
真不明白怎么会让你穿上军装
I can't believe they let you wear a uniform.
我的责任到此为止，我已经尽了力
I'm not gonna feel responsible for this. I did everything I could.
你去监狱过你的美好生活好了
You're going to Leavenworth for the better part of your life.
和我没半点关系
And you know what? I don't give a shit.
长官离开房间时你怎么不敬礼？
What happened to saluting an officer when he leaves the room?
开门
Open it up.
真不敢相信，真不敢相信
I don't believe it. I don't believe it.
就因为恨我他宁可去监狱
Dawson's gonna go to jail just to spite me.
没问题，他想自寻死路是他的事
Fine. If he wants to jump off a cliff, that's his business.
我可不想陪他去送死 怎样才能给他另找个律师？
I'm not gonna hold his hand on the way. I wanna get him a new lawyer. How?
明早传讯时提出申请就是
Just make a motion tomorrow morning at the arraignment.
法官会问你是否要提出答辩…
The judge will ask you if you want to enter a plea...
你就说希望另行指派律师
and you tell him that you want to have new counsel assigned.
就这样吧
That's that.
还有，当你要求法官另找律师时…
One thing, though. When you ask the judge for new counsel...
丹尼，记住一定要客气点
Danny, be sure and ask nicely.
你想要我怎么做？ 要你让他们接受庭审
What doyou want from me? I want you to let them be judged.
要你站起来进行辩护
I want you to stand up and make an argument.
辩护对屠杀越南人的战犯没用
An argument that didn't work for Calley at My Lai.
对纽伦堡的纳粹分子也没用
An argument that didn't work for the Nazis at Nuremburg.
看在上帝份上，山姆
Oh, for Christ's sake, Sam.
你真认为这是一码事吗？
Do you really think that's the same as two teenage Marines...
他们从不怀疑执行命令有什么错
executing a routine order they never believed would result in harm?
他们可不是纳粹分子
These guys aren't the Nazis.
现在争没用，丹尼，除非你上庭辩护
Don't look now, Danny, but you're making an argument.
是啊，是啊，明早我就给他们找个新律师
Yeah, yeah. Tomorrow morning I get them a new attorney.
你干嘛这样害怕做律师？
Why are you so afraid to be a lawyer?
是你父亲的期望太高了吗？
Were Daddy's expectations really that high?
得了，别跟我来这套父父子子的激将法
Oh, please. Spare me the psycho-babble father bullshit!
他们会有满意的结果，不过要靠别的律师
Dawson and Downey will have their day in court, but with another lawyer.
别的律师不够好，他们需要你
Another lawyer won't be good enough. They need you.
你知道怎么赢 你知道他们有冤情，你知道怎么才能赢
You know how to win. You know they have a case, and you know how to win.
你一走了之等于决定了他们的命运
If you walk away from this now, you've sealed their fate.
圣地亚哥身亡之时 他们的命运就已经注定了
Their fate was sealed the moment Santiago died.
你相信他们有冤情吗？ 你和道森都活在梦想世界里
Do you believe they have a case? You and Dawson. You both live in the same dream world.
问题不在于我相信什么
It doesn't matter what I believe.
而在于我能证明什么
It only matters what I can prove.
所以别说我知道什么不知道什么
So, please, don't tell me what I know and don't know!
我只知道法律
I know the law!
你对法律一无所知
You know nothing about the law.
你是个二手车推销员，丹尼
You're a used car salesman, Daniel.
你做律师只配处理交通纠纷
You're an ambulance chaser with a rank.
一无是处是你的谋生之道
You're nothing. Live with that.
所以我告诉邓肯…
So I told Duncan...
如果你想上庭，我会申请要求取证…
"If you wanna take this to court I'm gonna file nine discovery motions...
你就得因为一个九旬老翁看错特拉华州 的保险条款花上一年时间来组织书面材料
and you're gonna spend a year going blind on paperwork... because a 90-year-old man misread the Delaware insurance code."
然后呢？ 十五分钟后他回了电话
So what happened? He calls back 15 minutes later.
他说“庭外和解好了”
He says, "Let's make a deal."
全体起立
All rise.
哪个案子？
Where are we?
诉讼号 411275VR-5 一案
Docket number 411275VR-5.
美国政府起诉哈罗德・道森准下士…
The United States v. Lance Corporal Harold W. Dawson...
和一等兵劳登・多尼
and Private First Class Louden Downey.
罪名为谋杀，同谋策划谋杀…
The accused are charged with murder, conspiracy to commit murder...
以及对一名陆战队员行为不当
and conduct unbecoming a United States Marine.
辩方有什么意见吗？
Does the defense wish to enter a plea?
是的
Yeah.
他们没有罪
They're not guilty.
提请进行无罪答辩
Enter a plea of not guilty for the accused.
现在宣布休庭，三周后上午十点…
We'll adjourn until 1000, three weeks from today...
在最高军事法庭重新开庭审理
at which time this general court-martial will reconvene.
为什么一名只有九个月经验 和资历的中尉…
Why does a lieutenant junior grade with ninth months'experience...
会被指派为一起谋杀案作辩护律师？
and a track record for plea bargaining get assigned a murder case?
难道这样就能避免对簿公堂吗？
Would it be so that it never sees the inside of a courtroom?
晚上七点到我家找找答案
We'll work out of my apartment every night, 7:00.
乔，记住带一盒便笺 六盒红笔和六盒黑笔
Jo, pick up a carton of legal pads, half a dozen boxes of red and black pens.
山姆，带几盏台灯来 准备一份初步的验尸报告
Sam, get a couple of desk lamps. I need a preliminary medical profile.
乔，把道森，多尼和圣地亚哥 所有的训练审核报告找来
Jo, we need all proficiency and conduct reports on Dawson, Downey and Santiago.
我只有可可饮料和汽水…
The only thing I have to eat is Yoo-hoo and Cocoa Puffs...
想要其他饮料自己带
so if you want anything else, bring it with you.
行吗？ 好的
Okay? Yeah.
原来法庭就是这个样子
So this is what a courtroom looks like.
你和海军调查处的朋友说过吗？
Were you able to speak to your friend at the N.I. S?
说过，她说如果马金森不想被找到…
Yeah. She said if Markinson doesn't want to be found...
我们就别想找到他
we're not gonna find him.
哪怕马金森就在你面前你也认不出
She said I could be Markinson, and you wouldn't know it.
你是马金森吗？
Are you Markinson?
不是，我也不是马金森
I'm not Markinson.
那你我都排除在外了
That's two down.
怎么了？
What?
我想知道，现在有乔安妮帮忙…
I'm just wondering, now that Joanne's on this...
你是不是还需要我
I'm just wondering if you still need me.
他们只是执行命令 是不合法的命令
They were following orders. An illegal order.
你认为他们知道这命令不合法吗？
Do you think they knew it was an illegal order?
问题在于凡是正直的人都会拒绝…
It doesn't matter what they knew. Any decent person would have refused...
他们无权怀疑上级的命令
They're not permitted to question orders.
那干嘛要偷偷摸摸？干嘛要用代码？
Then what's the secret? Huh? What are the magic words?
我每天都下命令…
I give orders every day...
我们有棒球比赛和军乐队
We have softball games and marching bands.
可他们呆的地方得穿迷彩服 不然就可能被当成靶子
They work at a place where you have to wear camouflage or you might get shot!
我需要你
I need you.
做调查你比我强 而且你知道怎样安排证人
You're better at research than I am, and you know how to prepare a witness.
我带来了验尸报告，还有中餐，先吃点吧
I've got medical reports and Chinese food. I say we eat first.
怎么了？
What?
有没有宫保鸡丁？
You got any kung pao chicken?
我们要强调的是… 没人能证明那块抹布下过毒
This is our defense... intent. No one can prove there was poison on the rag.
“红色条规”在关达那摩湾见怪不怪
Code Red... they're common and accepted in Guantanamo Bay.
而命令…Ａ：是肯德瑞克下的 Ｂ：他们必须服从
The order... A: Kendrick gave it, B: They had to follow it.
就这些 动机呢？
That's it. What about motive?
这一点我们处于下风
We're a little weak on motive. They had one.
这并不表示他们有罪 别激动
That doesn't mean they're guilty. Relax.
我们会应付好开枪事件
We'll deal with the fenceline shooting when it comes up.
开始吧，别管圣地亚哥的具体死因…
Let's start with intent. I don't want to know what made Santiago die.
只需要证明有可能是毒药之外的因素
I just want to show it could've been something other than poison.
乔，找医生了解和乳酸中毒有关的一切
Jo, talk to doctors. Find out everything there is to know about lactic acidosis.
我是华盛顿最高军法处的盖洛维少校
This is Lieutenant Commander Galloway with the JAG Corps in Washington.
我想找出马修・马金森中校的下落
I've been trying to track down a Lieutenant Colonel Matthew Markinson.
医生，有没有任何外伤？
Doctor, was there any sign of external damage?
没有擦伤？没有伤口？淤伤和骨折呢？
No scrapes? No cuts? Bruises? Broken bones?
有没有暴力痕迹？ 难道死亡还不足以证明吗？
Was there any sign of violence? You mean, other than the dead body?
见鬼，我忽略了该死的时间问题
Shit, I walk into that every goddamn time.
他命令我和道森准下士 对威廉执行“红色条规”
He ordered me and Lance Corporal Dawson to give Willie a Code Red.
回答还得更快一些
Answers still have to come much faster.
马马虎虎，但最后一句 听起来感觉象在编造事实
This Iowa farm boy thing will play for a while... but in the end, it sounds like he's searching for the truth.
没错，要说“一等兵圣地亚哥”
He's right. From now on, Willie is Private Santiago.
别说“威廉”，那会让陪审团产生 对我们不利的情绪，懂吗？
You start calling him Willie, and all of a sudden he's a person... who's got a mother who's gonna miss him, okay?
下午已经拟定了陪审团
They drew the court members this afternoon.
七男两女，五个海军，四个陆战队员
Seven men, two women, five Navy, four Marines.
全是资深军官，两个女的都有孩子
All officers with line experience. Neither of the women have children.
不太妙，我们对此无能为力
That's a bad break. There's nothing we can do.
有陪审团就不单纯是法律的问题了
My father always said a jury trial is not just about the law.
而圣地亚哥的无辜身亡会让…
It's about assigning blame. Santiago's dead, and he shouldn't be.
陪审团主张有人得为此承担罪责
These nine people are gonna insist that someone be blamed for that.
是当事人还是肯德瑞克…
Ross is handing them our clients. We're gonna hand them Kendrick.
就得看律师如何“推销”自己的观点了
This is about a sales pitch. It's gonna be won by the lawyers.
记住表情要严肃，在陪审团面前不要畏缩
So remember, poker faces. Don't flinch in front of the court members.
态度要强硬，别低着头如坐针毡
Something doesn't go our way, don't hang your head or shift in your seat.
不管出现什么意外都要让人感觉成竹在胸
Whatever happens, you have to look like it's exactly what you knew would happen.
递文件给我时… 动作要迅速而从容
If you pass me documents... Do it swiftly and don't look eager.
上庭时别打香水，那会分散我的注意力
Don't wear that perfume in court. Wrecks my concentration.
真的吗？
Really?
我是说山姆
I was talking to Sam.
几点了？
What time is it?
该回家了，好好睡一觉
It's time to go home. Try to get some sleep.
能送我一程吗？
Yeah. Give me a ride?
没问题
Sure.
你真是个好人，查理布朗（卡通人物）
You're a good man, Charlie Brown.
法庭上见，大律师
I'll seeyou in court, counselor.
丹尼，我… 不用说了
Danny, I... You don't have to say it.
我们有过分歧，我说过一些无心的话
We've had our differences. I said some things I didn't mean.
你也是，但你很高兴我能接下这个案子
You said some things you didn't mean, but you're happy I stuck with the case.
如果过去三周以来 你对我多了一些敬意…
And if you've gained a certain respect for me over the last three weeks...
我当然会为此而高兴
of course, I'm happy about that.
但用不着太放在心上
But we don't have to make a whole big deal out of it.
你喜欢我我也不会要求你说出来
If you like me, I won't make you say it.
我只是想提醒你明天别穿错袜子
I was just gonna tell you to wear matching socks tomorrow.
好的，很重要提示
Okay. Good tip.
那就万事俱备了
We're ready.
最好相信这一点
Better believe it.
我们要大获全胜
We're gonna get creamed.
凯菲中尉？ 什么事？
Lieutenant Kaffee? Yes?
你会救我们的儿子对吧？
You are gonna save our son, aren't you?
我会尽力而为
I'll do my best.
丹尼，我给你介绍一下 劳登的姨妈詹妮・米勒
Danny, I'd like you to meet Ginny Miller, Louden's aunt.
你就是詹妮姨妈？
You're Aunt Ginny? Uh-huh.
不好意思，没想到你这么年轻
I'm sorry. I was expecting someone older.
彼此彼此
So was I.
给个机会掷硬币定输赢吧
Last chance. I'll flip you for it.
全体起立 太晚了
All rise. Too late.
最高军事法庭，请所有在场人员…
All those having business with this general court-martial...
坐到前面来，主持审判的是…
stand forward and you shall be heard.
朱利叶斯・亚历山大・伦道夫将军
Colonel Julius Alexander Randolph is presiding.
控方准备好作公开陈述了吗？
Is the government prepared to make an opening statement?
是的，大人
Yes, sir.
本案事实如下：
The facts of the case are these:
九月六日午夜，被告潜入其队友…
On midnight of September 6, the accused entered the barracks room...
一等兵威廉・圣地亚哥的房间
of their platoon mate, P.F.C. William Santiago.
将其弄醒后捆住其手脚…
They woke him up, tied his arms and legs with tape...
并强行将一块抹布塞进他的喉咙
and forced a rag into his throat.
几分钟后 一种名为“乳酸中毒”的化学反应…
A few minutes later, a chemical reaction called lactic acidosis...
导致其肺部出血…
caused his lungs to begin bleeding.
因此而窒息…
He drowned in his own blood...
至午夜十二点三十七分被确认死亡
and was pronounced dead at 37 minutes past midnight.
以上为本案事实经过，绝无虚假
These are the facts of the case, and they are undisputed.
各位将会听到被告道森准下士…
That's right. The story I've just told you...
以及一等兵多尼的陈述…
is the exact same story you're gonna hear from Lance Corporal Dawson...
与我刚才所说的完全一致
and it's the exact same story you're gonna hear from Private Downey.
此外，我将向各位证实…
Furthermore, the government will also demonstrate...
被告在抹布上下过毒…
that the accused soaked the rag in poison...
而且是怀着杀人动机潜入圣地亚哥的房间
and entered Santiago's room with motive and intent to kill.
现在，凯菲中尉…
Now, Lieutenant Kaffee...
会努力玩弄一些小魔术来混淆视听
is gonna try and pull off a little magic act here.
他会用令人震惊的所谓“军规”…
He's gonna try a little misdirection.
某些听起来很正式的术语…
He's gonna astonish you with stories of rituals...
试着误导在场的各位…
and dazzle you with official-sounding terms...
例如“红色条规”
like "Code Red."
甚至还有可能牵扯上几位军官
He might even try to cut into a few officers for you.
他没有证据，一点证据都没有 不过会很有娱乐性
He'll have no evidence, mind you, none, but it's gonna be entertaining.
但是最终，世上所有的魔术…
And when we get to the end, all the magic in the world...
都无法让人忽视一个事实…
will not have been able to divert your attention from the fact...
威廉・圣地亚哥死了 是道森和多尼杀死了他
that Willie Santiago is dead and Dawson and Downey killed him.
这是本案的事实，是无法否认的
These are the facts of the case, and they are undisputed.
凯菲中尉
Lieutenant Kaffee.
抹布没下过毒，而且没有杀人动机
There was no poison on the rag, and there was no intent to kill.
不管用什么方式去证明都是徒劳的 因为这不是事实
Any attempt to prove otherwise is futile'cause it just aingt true.
那天夜里道森和多尼 进入圣地亚哥的房间…
When Dawson and Downey went into Santiago's room that night...
不是因为报复或敌意
it wasn't because of vengeance or hatred.
不是为了杀人或伤人，也不是为了寻开心
It wasn't to kill or harm, and it wasn't because they were looking for kicks.
因为他们是奉命行事
It's because it was what they were ordered to do.
让我重复一次
Let me say that again.
因为他们是奉命行事
It's because it was what theywere ordered to do.
在其他地方这无足轻重…
Out in the real world that means nothing...
哪怕在这…海军学院也没什么大不了
and here at the Washington Navy Yard it doesn't mean a whole lot more.
但如果一名 古巴关达那摩湾Ｗ步兵警卫连的…
But if you're a Marine assigned to Rifle Security Company Windward...
海军陆战队员接到一个命令…
Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and you're given an order...
不执行就得卷铺盖走人
you follow it or you packyour bags.
这一点不要弄错
Make no mistake about it.
哈・道森和劳・多尼今天坐在各位面前…
Harold Dawson and Louden Downey are sitting before you today...
是因为他们履行了自己的职责
because they did their job.
控方要传讯第一个证人吗？
Is the government ready to call its first witness?
庭上，控方请求传召Ｒ・Ｃ・米盖尔先生
If it please the court, the government calls Mr. R.C. McGuire.
米盖尔先生，请举起你的右手
Mr. McGuire, would you raise your right hand, please?
你愿意发誓你在法庭上…
Do you solemnly swear that the testimony you give this general court-martial...
所说的一切完全属实，绝无虚假吗？
will be the truth, the whole truth and nothing but the truth?
我发誓 请坐下，先生
I do. Have a seat, please, sir.
请说出你的全名以及职业
Would you state your full name and occupation, for the record?
罗伯特・Ｃ・米盖尔 海军调查处特别官员
Robert C. McGuire, Special Agent, Naval Investigative Service.
米盖尔先生，今年九月三日 你的办公室是否收到过一等兵…
Mr. McGuire, did your office receive a letter from P.F.C. William Santiago...
威廉・圣地亚哥的信？
on 3 September of this year?
是的 信里面说什么？
We did. What did that letter say?
是说他所在单位的一名队员 用所持武器在边界向境外开枪
That a member of Santiago's unit had fired his weapon over the fenceline.
有没有具体说明是谁？
Was that Marine identified in the letter?
没有，我通知指挥官杰赛普上校…
No. I notified the barracks C.O. Colonel Jessup...
我将会前往调查
that I would be coming down to investigate.
调查结果呢？
And what did you find?
记录显示只有一名哨兵归还武器时…
The shift reported only one sentry returned his weapon to the switch...
少了一发子弹
with a round of ammunition missing.
是谁？ 哈罗德・道森准下士
Who was that? Lance Corporal Harold Dawson.
该你问了
Your witness.
米盖尔先生 你向道森询问过开枪事件吗？
Mr. McGuire, have you questioned Dawson about the fenceline shooting?
问过，他声称对方有不利于他的行动
Yes. He claims to have been engaged in some manner by the enemy.
你不相信他吗？ 这不关我的…
You don'believe him? It's not my place...
为什么道森准下士触犯了军规却没有 因为无故向敌方开枪受到起诉呢？
Lance Corporal Dawson's been charged with a number of crimes. Why wasn't he charged with firing at the enemy without cause?
没有足够的证据来起诉
There wasn't enough evidence to support such a charge.
谢谢
Thank you.
米盖尔先生，我不明白…
Mr. McGuire, I don't understand what you mean when you say...
“没有足够的证据”是指什么
"There wasn't enough evidence to support such a charge."
你有威廉・圣地亚哥的信
You had William Santiago's letter.
圣地亚哥是唯一的目击者
Santiago was the only eyewitness.
我没来得及询问他 所以不知道他看到了什么
I never had the chance to interview him, so I don't know what he saw.
我们永远不会知道了，是不是？ 是的
And now we'll never know, will we, Mr. McGuire?
我问完了 证人请退下
No more questions. The witness is excused.
海军陆战队Ｗ步兵警卫连二Ｂ排…
Corporal Carl Edward Hammaker, Marine Barracks...
卡尔・爱德华・汉梅克下士
Rifle Security Company Windward, Second Platoon Bravo.
下士，九月六日下午肯德瑞克上尉 召集二排开会时你是否在场？
Corporal, were you present at a meeting that Lieutenant Kendrick held... on the afternoon of September 6 with the members of the Second Platoon?
在场，长官
Yes, sir.
能说说会议的内容是什么吗？
Would you tell the court the substance of that meeting?
肯德瑞克上尉说我们排有个告密的…
Lieutenant Kendrick told us we had an informer in our group...
一等兵圣地亚哥越级…
that Private Santiago had gone outside the chain of command...
向海军调查处举报排里的一名队员
and reported to the N.I.S. On a member of our platoon.
这是不是让你很气愤？ 你可以说实话，下士
Did that make you mad? You can tell the truth, Corporal.
你是不是很生气？ 是的，长官
Did it make you mad? Yes, sir.
有多生气？
How mad?
一等兵圣地亚哥违背了 我们深信不疑的一条规矩，长官
Private Santiago betrayed a code we believe in very deeply, sir.
其他队员有没有生气？ 反对无根据的假设
Were the other squad members angry? Object. Speculation.
比方说道森和多尼？ 控方律师这是在…
Were Dawson and Downey? Is the government counsel...
直接要求证人证实我当事人的想法吗？
honestly asking the witness to testify as to how my clients felt?
反对有效
Sustained.
下士，肯德瑞克上尉 在会上是否下过什么命令？
Corporal, did Lieutenant Kendrick leave a standing order at that meeting?
是的，长官 什么命令？
Yes, sir. What was it?
他明令我们不得擅自处理这件事
Well, it was clear that he didn't want us taking matters into our own hands.
是什么命令？
What was the order?
长官，他说不许碰圣地亚哥
Sir, he said Santiago wasn't to be touched.
该你问了
Your witness.
汉梅克下士，散会五分钟后 你是否去过道森和多尼的房间？
Corporal Hammaker, were you in Dawson and Downey's barracks... five minutes after this meeting?
没有，长官
No, sir.
谢谢，我问完了
Thanks. I have no more questions.
证人请退下
The witness is excused.
控方请求传雷蒙德・汤马斯下士
The government calls Corporal Raymond Thomas.
我知道罗斯上尉是打算传召…
I understand Captain Ross is planning on calling all the other members...
Ｗ步兵警卫连的所有队员来作证
of Rifle Security Company Windward to testify.
显然凯菲中尉的辩护重点…
In light of the defense Lieutenant Kaffee is planning to mount...
和排长的明确指示有相当大的关系
the explicit instructions of a platoon leader seems particularly relevant.
辩方可以同意全部二十二名证人…
The defense is willing to concede that all 22 witnesses...
的证词和汉梅克下士基本一致…
will testify substantially as Corporal Hammaker did...
只要控方同意九月六日下午四点二十分…
if the government is willing to concede that none of them...
他们谁都不在道森和多尼的房间
were in Dawson and Downey's room at 16:20 on September 6.
上尉？
Captain?
控方可以同意
The government will stipulate.
现在休庭，你可以 明天传讯你的下一位证人
Then we'll adjourn for the day. You can call your next witness tomorrow.
全体起立
All rise.
我要再演习一下医生那段
I want to go over the doctor again.
还是直接了当吧 那我们已经演习过了
We're taking the right approach. We've been over this already.
听我说，三点钟时斯通医生 还说不知道圣地亚哥的死因
Listen to me. 3:00... Stone says he doesn't know what killed Santiago.
等见过杰赛普之后 五点钟时他却说是中毒
Then he meets with Jessup, and at 5:00 he says it was poison?
医生没有说实话 哦，真是个救星
The doctor's not telling the truth. Oh, that's a relief!
但我作辩时总不能说他是在撒谎吧
I was afraid I wouldn't be able to use the "liar, liar, pants on fire" defense.
我们无法证明他受过胁迫 还是温习一下手头掌握的材料吧
We can't prove coercion. Let's go over what we have, okay?
一等兵圣地亚哥 是零点十二分分送到急救室的…
Private Santiago was admitted to the E.R. At 0012...
在零点三十七分被确认死亡
and he was pronounced dead at 0037.
斯通医生，什么是乳酸中毒？
Dr. Stone, what is lactic acidosis?
如果 肌肉及人体的其他细胞燃烧的是糖…
If the muscles and other cells of the body burn sugar...
而不是氧，体内就会产生乳酸
instead of oxygen, lactic acid is produced.
正是乳酸导致了圣地亚哥肺出血
That lactic acid is what caused Santiago's lungs to bleed.
通常肌肉和其他细胞要多长时间…
Normally, how long does it take for the muscles and other cells...
才开始燃烧糖而不是氧？
to begin burning sugar instead of oxygen?
二十到三十分钟
Twenty to thirty minutes.
是什么原因 加速了圣地亚哥肌肉的这种反应？
And what caused this process to be sped up in Santiago's muscles?
某种摄入性中毒
An ingested poison of some kind.
法官大人，我反对，证人是在推断
Your Honor, we object at this point. The witness is speculating.
斯通中校是医学专家
Commander Stone is an expert medical witness.
他的观点不能认为是推断
In this courtroom, his opinion is not considered speculation.
斯通中校是内科医生，不是犯罪学专家
Commander Stone is an internist, not a criminologist.
医学事实在法庭上不是决定性的
The medical facts here are ultimately inconclusive.
我相信你可以通过交互提问证明这一点
A point I'm confident you'll illustrate to the court under cross-examination.
所以应该不介意我们暂时认可其观点
So I'm sure you won't mind if his opinion is admitted now.
当然，大人
Not at all, sir.
斯通医生 威廉・圣地亚哥是死于中毒吗？
Dr. Stone, did Willie Santiago die of poisoning?
毫无疑问
Absolutely.
你知道化验室和验尸官的报告 都显示没有毒药的痕迹吗？
You're aware that the lab and coroner's report show no traces of poison?
知道 那你怎么证明…
Yes, I am. Then how do you justify...
严格说来有很多种毒素…
There are literally dozens of toxins which are virtually undetectable...
在人体组织中是无法检测到的
both in the human body and on a fabric.
在这一案例中酸中毒症状是显而易见的
The nature of the acidosis is the compelling factor on this issue.
谢谢，长官
Thank you, sir.
中校，如果有人患了某种病…
Commander, is it possible for a person to have an affliction...
在某种情形下… 有没有可能加速酸中毒的过程呢？
some sort of condition... which might speed up the process of acidosis?
有可能吗，中校？
Commander, is it possible?
有可能
It's possible.
在什么情形下呢？
What might some of those conditions be?
如果患有冠状动脉紊乱…
If a person had a coronary disorder...
或是大脑紊乱，就会加速该过程
or a cerebral disorder, the process would be more rapid.
如果我有冠状动脉问题 在嘴里塞上一块干净的抹布…
If I had a coronary condition and a clean rag was placed in my mouth...
塞得非常深，我的细胞是否有可能…
and the rag was pushed too far down, is it possible that my cells...
在拿掉抹布后继续燃烧糖分呢？
would continue burning sugar after the rag was taken out?
那得是病情非常严重的情况下
It would have to be a very serious condition.
是否有可能病情非常严重…
Is it possible to have a serious coronary condition...
但症状很轻微，以至于在常规的…
where the warning signals were so mild as to escape a physician...
体检时被医生忽略呢？
during a routine medical exam?
有可能，但还是会有迹象
Possibly. There would still be symptoms, though.
何种迹象？ 有好几百种…
What kind of symptoms? There are hundreds...
胸口疼？ 是的
Chest pains? Yes.
气喘？ 是的
Shortness of breath? Yes.
疲劳？ 当然
Fatigue? Of course.
医生，这是你的签名吗？
Doctor, is this your signature?
是的
Yes, it is.
这上面表明 应限制给圣地亚哥分配任务
This is an order for Private Santiago to be put on restrictive duty.
请你读一下你写在下面的备注好吗？
Would you read your handwritten remarks at the bottom of the page, please?
初步测试，阴性，患者胸口疼痛…
"Initial testing, negative. Patient complains of chest pains...
气喘且易疲劳
shortness of breath and fatigue.
每周跑步的距离应限制在五英里以内
Restricted from running distances over five miles for one week."
中校，有没有可能 圣地亚哥患有严重的疾病…
Commander, isn't it possible that Santiago had a serious condition...
而这种疾病会导致化学反应的加速？ 不会
and it was that condition that caused the accelerated chemical reaction?
不可能吗？
It's not possible?
是的，我亲自给每个人 做过彻底的身体检查
I personally give each man a thorough physical examination.
一等兵圣地亚哥各方面都很健康
Private Santiago was given a clean bill of health.
所以非得是中毒对吧，中校？
That's why it had to be poison, right, Commander?
因为如果你让一个 冠状动脉有严重问题的人出任务…
'Cause if you put a man with a serious coronary condition on duty...
而这人死于与心脏有关的事故…
and that man died from a heart-related incident...
你就会有大麻烦，是吗？
you'd have a lot to answer for, wouldn't you, Doctor?
反对，请求驳回 反对有效
Object! Move to strike. Sustained.
我问完了，法官先生
I have no more questions, Your Honor.
斯通医生，你获得行医执照已有十七年
Dr. Stone, you've held a medical license for 17 years.
通过了内科医学委员会的鉴定
You're Board-certified in internal medicine.
在一家为五千四百二十六人服务的医院 任内科主管
You are chief of internal medicine at a hospital which serves 5,426 people.
以你的医学专业观点来看 圣地亚哥是死于中毒吗？
In your professional medical opinion, was Willie Santiago poisoned?
辩方重申反对斯通中校的证词…
We renew our objection to Commander Stone's testimony...
并要求从笔录中撤回
and ask that it be stricken from the record.
请求陪审团对该证人的证词不予考虑
We further ask the court members to lend no weight to this witness's testimony.
反对无效，予以驳回
The objection is overruled.
辩方强烈反对并要求进行合议…
The defense strenuously objects and requests an 802 conference...
这样庭上可以有机会在判决前听到辩论
so that His Honor might have a chance to hear discussion before ruling.
辩方的反对我已经听到，反对无效
The objection of the defense has been heard and overruled.
请求重新考虑 你的反对已被记录下来
Move to reconsider. Your objection is noted.
该证人是一位专家，法庭要听听他的观点
The witness is an expert, and the court will hear his opinion!
斯通医生，以你的专业经验所见…
Dr. Stone, in your expert, professional opinion...
威廉・圣地亚哥是死于中毒吗？
was Willie Santiago poisoned?
是的
Yes.
谢谢，长官，我问完了
Thank you, sir. I have no more questions.
中校，你可以下去了
Commander, you may step down.
控方请求休庭 同时请求保留传讯特别证人的权力
Please the court, while we reserve the right to call rebuttal witnesses... the government rests.
本案押后至十九日星期一上午十点再审…
We'll stand in recess until 1000, Monday the 19th...
届时请辩方传第一证人出庭
at which time, the defense will call its first witness.
全体起立
All rise.
“我强烈反对”？
"I strenuously object"?
那有什么用？ “反对予以驳回”
Is that how it works? "Objection overruled."
“不，不…我坚持反对”
"No, no. I strenuously object."
“哦，既然你坚持反对 那我会予以重新考虑
"Oh, well, if you strenuously object, then I should take time to reconsider."
至少记入了笔录
I got it on the record.
可也让陪审团以为我们怕那个医生
You also got the court members thinking we're afraid of the doctor.
反对一次就能让人知道他不是犯罪学专家
You object once, so they can hear us say he's not a criminologist.
不断重申就让人感觉 这是律师的古怪花招了
You keep after it, and suddenly it looks like a bunch of fancy lawyer tricks.
书上的法律和庭上的法律是两回事
It's the difference between paper law and trial law.
结果法官只好强调斯通是专家
You even had the judge saying Stone was an expert!
她已经犯了错，我们不要再提了
She made a mistake. Let's not relive it.
我要给我妻子打电话，晚上见
I'm gonna go call my wife. I'll see you tonight.
你为什么这样恨他们？
Why do you hate them so much?
他们以强凌弱，这是事实
They beat up on a weakling. That's all they did.
其他的全都是废话
The rest of this is just smoke-filled coffee house crap.
他们折磨过一个虚弱的年轻人
They tortured and tormented a weaker kid!
因为不喜欢他就杀了他
They didn't like him, so they killed him.
为什么？因为他跑得不快
And why? Because he couldn't run very fast!
好了，今晚大家都休息吧
All right. Everybody take the night off.
对不起 我知道
I'm sorry. I know.
我们连着三周半每天工作二十个小时
We've been working 20 hours a day for three and halfweeks straight.
就休息一晚，去看看你太太和女儿
Just take the night off. Go see your wife, your daughter.
乔，你去…
Jo, go do...
反正不用来，你想干什么就干什么吧
whatever it is you do when you're not here.
明天星期几？ 星期六
What day is tomorrow? Saturday.
我们十点碰头
We start at 10:00.
你为什么这样维护他们？
Why do you like them so much?
因为他们在守卫边疆…
'Cause they stand on a wall...
而且保证 “今晚有我站岗，没什么能伤害你们”
and they say, "Nothing's gonna hurt you tonight, not on my watch."
别担心那个医生，审判要星期一才开始
Don't worry about the doctor. This trial starts Monday.
有两人出局，安达将球击向左中场
1 and 2 with two out. Anda line drive to left center.
克比上垒失败
Kirby racing. He won't get there.
第三个跑垒员是卡尔・瑞普肯…
And rounding third is Cal Ripken... and the Twins'streak is over.
One strike away, and Randy Milligan feels right now like Hulk Hogan.
很抱歉打扰你，我该先打个电话
I'm sorry to bother you. I should've called first.
没关系，我只是在看球赛，进来吧
No, I was just watching a ball game. Come on in.
我是想…你愿意和我一起去吃晚饭吗？
I was wondering if... How you'd feel about my taking you to dinner tonight?
你是想和我约会吗？ 不是
Are you asking me out on a date? No.
听上去你是想约我 不是
Sounded like you were asking me on a date.
以前有人约过我，听起来就是那个意思
I've been asked out on dates before, and that's what it sounded like.
喜欢海鲜吗？我知道一个好地方
Do you like seafood? I know a good seafood place.
我第三件案子是一起酗酒闹事案
My third case was a drunk and disorderly.
花了九个星期 我把那晚在酒吧的三十一个人都找遍了
It lasted nine weeks. I rounded up 31 people from the bar that night.
酗酒闹事花了九个星期？ 控方想怎么判？
Nine weeks on a D and D? What was the prosecutor offering?
十五天
Fifteen days.
当事人真是免遭大难
You sure hustled the shit out of him.
后来他们把我调到了内政部
Well, after that they moved me to Internal Affairs.
不能怪他们 我…
Tough to blame them. Where I have earned...
得过两枚立功奖章和两次奖状
two meritorious service medals and two letters of commendation.
你干嘛总是和我说你的过去？
Why are you always giving me your resume?
我想要你承认我是个好律师
Because I want you to think I'm a good lawyer.
我承认
I do.
不，你没有
No, you don't.
我觉得你是个了不起的律师
I think you're an exceptional lawyer.
我注意过陪审团 你能引起他们的共鸣，他们喜欢你
I watch the court members. They respond to you. They like you.
你令他们信服，我觉得道森和多尼…
I see you convincing them, and I think Dawson and Downey...
的下半辈子就得靠你了
are gonna end up owing their lives toyou.
乔，我觉得…
Jo, I think...
你应该对我们会输的事实现好心理准备
I think you should prepare yourself for the fact that we're gonna lose.
罗斯说的那些都是事实
Ross's opening statement... it was all true.
我们可以暂时假设他们是奉命行事
Let's pretend for a minute that it would actually matter... that the guys were given an order.
但无法证明确有其事
I can't prove it ever happened.
我们可以继续设法去证明…
We'll keep doing what we're doing and we'll put on a show...
但我们掌握的所有证据 都是两个被指控谋杀的人提供的
but all we have is the testimony of two people accused of murder.
我们会找到马金森
We'll find Markinson.
乔，我们会输，而且会输得很惨
Jo, we're gonna lose, and we're gonna lose huge.
古巴关达那摩湾海军陆战队Ｗ连 杰弗瑞・欧文・巴恩斯下士
Corporal Jeffrey Owen Barnes, Marine Barracks Windward... Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.
巴恩斯下士，请说明一下 队员会因哪些理由被执行“红色条规”
Corporal Barnes, name some reasons why a Marine would receive a Code Red.
排里或连队开会时迟到
Being late for platoon or company meetings.
营房总是乱七八糟，跑步时掉队
Keeping his barracks in disorder. Falling back on a run.
你接受过“红色条规”吗？ 是的，长官
Have you ever received a Code Red? Yes, sir.
我在进行分组突袭训练时武器滑落了
We were doing seven-man assault drills, and my weapon slipped.
因为当时气温超过一百度 我的手心全是汗…
It was'cause it was over 100 degrees, and my palms were sweaty...
而我忘了象学过的那样抹上松香
and I'd forgotten to use the resin like we were taught.
结果呢？
What happened?
当天夜里我的队友用毯子蒙住我…
That night, the guys in my squad threw a blanket over me...
狠狠揍了我五分钟…
took turns punching me in the arm for five minutes...
然后在我的手上涂上胶水
then they poured glue on my hands.
这很管用 因为从那以后我的武器再没有脱过手
And it worked too,'cause I aingt never dropped my weapon since.
一等兵圣地亚哥开会时迟过到吗？
Was Private Santiago ever late for platoon meetings?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
他的营房很乱吗？ 是的，长官
Was his barracks ever in disorder? Yes, sir.
他跑步时掉过队吗？ 每次都是，长官
Did he ever fall back on a run? All the time, sir.
九月六日晚上之前 他有没有接受过“红色条规”？
Did he ever, prior to the night of September 6, receive a Code Red?
没有，长官
No, sir.
从来没有？ 没有，长官
Never? No, sir.
你因为手掌出汗受过一次“红色条规”
You got a Code Red'cause your palms were sweaty.
为什么圣地亚哥 总是拖后腿却没受过一次呢？
Why didn't Santiago, this burden to his unit, ever get one?
因为道森不允许，长官
Dawson wouldn't allow it, sir.
道森不允许
Dawson wouldn't allow it.
大家都对圣地亚哥很凶，但没有碰过他
The guys talked tough about Santiago, but they wouldn't go near him.
因为都很怕道森
They were too afraid of Dawson.
反对，证人是在推断
Object. The witness is speculating.
我换个问法，杰弗瑞你想过 要对圣地亚哥执行“红色条规”吗？
I'll rephrase. Jeffrey, did you ever want to give Santiago a Code Red?
是的，长官 为什么没有呢？
Yes, sir. Why didn't you?
因为道森会收拾我，长官
'Cause Dawson would kick my butt, sir.
很好，现在轮到罗斯上尉问你话了
Good enough. Captain Ross is gonna ask you some questions now.
巴恩斯下士…
Corporal Barnes...
这有本新兵训练用的“陆战队纲要”
I hold here the Marine Outline for Recruit Training.
你熟悉这本书吗？ 是的，长官
Are you familiar with this book? Yes, sir.
你看过没有？ 看过，长官
Have you read it? Yes, sir.
好的，请你翻到 关于“红色条规”的章节行吗？
Would you turn to the chapter that deals with Code Reds, please?
只要翻到描述“红色条规”的那一页
Just flip to the page of the book that discusses Code Reds.
要知道，长官 “红色条规”是我们用的一个术语
Well, you see, sir, Code Red is a term that we use.
只限于关达那摩…
Just down in Gitmo...
好在还有本书
Oh, we're in luck, then.
古巴关达那摩湾 步兵警卫连行为规范守则
Standard Operating Procedure, Rifle Security Company, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.
我猜这本书里 会有“红色条规”的定义条款
I assume we'll find the term Code Red and its definition in that book.
没有，长官 没有？
No, sir.
下士，难道陆战队员…
Corporal Barnes, I'm a Marine.
没有书，没有手册 也没有制订规章制度…
Is there no book, no manual or pamphlet, no set of orders or regulations...
让大家明白执行“红色条规” 是陆战队员的职责之一吗？
that lets me know that as a Marine one of my duties is to perform Code Reds?
没有，长官，没这种书，长官
No, sir. No book, sir.
我问完了
No further questions.
下士，请你将书翻到…
Corporal, would you turn to the page in this book...
有餐厅位置说明的那一页
that says where the mess hall is, please?
凯菲中尉，书里没有这个，长官
Lieutenant Kaffee, that's not in the book, sir.
你是说 你在关达那摩期间从没吃过饭吗？
You mean to say in all your time at Gitmoyou've never had a meal?
不，长官，一日三餐都会吃，长官
No, sir. Three squares a day, sir.
这我就不懂了
I don't understand.
书里没说，那你怎么知道餐厅在哪？
How did you know where the mess hall was if it's not in this book?
在吃饭时间跟着大家一起去就能知道
Well, I guess I just followed the crowd at chow time, sir.
我问完了
No more questions.
巴恩斯下士，你可以下去了 谢谢，长官
Corporal Barnes, you may step down. Thank you, sir.
今晚七点，最后演练一下 对肯德瑞克的问话
7:00 tonight we'll do a final Kendrick review.
我要让他目瞪口呆
I want to slam-dunk this guy.
嘿，卢瑟
Hey, Luther.
“海军上将”，案子的进展如何？
Admiral, how's the big case going?
忙得团团转
Nose to the grindstone.
苍蝇都没法落在你身上 正是这样
No flies on you. A rolling stone gathers no moss.
鹿死谁手尚未可知
Well, it aingt over till the fat lady sings.
你可以再说一次
You can say that again.
鹿死谁手尚未可知
It aingt over till the fat lady sings. Till the fat lady sings.
说起来轻松
Walked into that one.
哦，我的天
Oh, Jesus Christ!
你没锁车门
You left the door unlocked.
你吓得我魂都没了 继续往前开
You scared the shit out of me. Just keep driving.
知道法庭想传讯你吗？
Are you aware you're under subpoena?
知道，我还知道 有两名陆战队员的命运掌握在你手中
Yes. I'm also aware that the lives of two Marines are in your hands.
因为我没能阻止事态的发展 所以只好来帮你一把
If there was something I could do about that, I would. But since I can't, all I can do is help you.
你知道些什么？ 所有细节
What do you know? I know everything.
是一次“红色条规”吗？ 是的
Was it a Code Red? Yes.
是肯德瑞克下的命令？ 是的
Did Kendrick give the order? Yes.
是你亲眼所见吗？ 用不着
Did you witness it? I didn't need to.
那你怎么知道？你根本不知道
Then how do you know? You know shit.
他决不会被调离基地
He was never gonna be transferred off that base.
杰赛普想让他留在基地，说要好好教训他
Jessup was gonna keep him on the base. He said he wanted him trained.
可调令是你签发的 我知道
The transfer order has your signature. Yeah, I know.
是圣地亚哥死后第五天 你们到古巴的当天早上签的
I signed it the morning you arrived in Cuba, five days after Santiago died.
我会为你争取举报人豁免权
I'm gonna get you a deal, some kind of immunity with the prosecutor.
四天后你要出面作证 把你知道的事情说出来
In about four days, you'll appear as a witness and tell what you know.
我给你找家旅馆，我们要从头来过
I'm gonna check you into a motel. We are gonna start from the beginning.
用不着协议，我也不需要豁免权
I don't want a deal, and I don't want immunity.
我只想让你知道 我为自己曾做过和正在做的事而自豪
I want you to know that I'm proud neither of what I've done or am doing.
他在哪？ “东北市区旅馆”
Where is he? The Downtown Lodge in Northeast.
要保证他的安全 是个好提议
I want him guarded. That's a good idea.
我的安全调查号码是 411527273 安全调查号？
My clearance code is 411527273. Clearance code?
谢谢 你有安全调查号吗？
Thank you. Do you have a clearance code?
我是乔・盖洛维，我要保护一个证人
This is Jo Galloway. I need to secure a witness.
总之他说 杰赛普在调离基地一事上撒了谎
Anyway, he also said that Jessup's lying about the transportation off the base.
杰赛普说最早的航班是第二天六点
Jessup said that 6:00 the next morning was the first flight leaving.
马金森说七小时之前就有飞机飞离基地
Markinson says there was a plane that left seven hours earlier.
我记得很清楚，你听到我说的话吗？
That was impressive. Did you hear what I said about the flight?
山姆，飞机何时起飞有记录可查对吗？
Sam, when a flight takes off, there's a record kept, right?
对，得找到基地指挥塔的航行日志
Yeah, you need the tower chiefs log from Gitmo.
把它找来 我们会赢的
Get it. We're gonna win.
还不知道马金森是否可靠 航行日志还在不在
We don't know who Markinson is. We don't know what the logbook will say.
你去做多尼的工作，我去向罗斯透露一下
You just concentrate on Downey. I'm gonna tell Ross where we are.
今天询问巴恩斯时表现真不错
Nice work today. Redirect on Barnes.
我找到了马金森 他在哪？
I have Markinson. Where is he?
“东北”的一个房间 有六个联邦密探守在门口
Motel room in Northeast with six Federal Marshalls outside his door.
马金森签发的调令是伪造的
The transfer that Markinson signed is phony.
杰赛普说最早的航班在早上六点是撒谎
Jessup's statement that the 6:00 a.m. Flight was the first available is a lie.
我们在查航空日志，啤酒
We're checking the tower chiefs log. I'd like a beer, please.
同时我要让肯德瑞克出庭 到时就有好戏可看了
In the meantime, I'm gonna put Kendrick on the stand and have some fun.
好吧，我有义务提醒你…
All right, I have an obligation to tell you...
如果没有适当的证据 想起诉肯德瑞克或杰赛普…
that if you accuse Kendrick or Jessup of any crime without proper evidence...
你会被军事法庭以渎职罪论处
you'll be subject to a court-martial for professional misconduct.
会记入你的档案 不管你以后找什么工作都摆脱不了
That's something that'll be stapled to every job application you ever fill out.
马金森靠不住，丹尼，他是个疯子
Markinson's not gonna hold up, Danny. He's a crazy man.
我这么说不是想吓你，是为你着想
I'm not saying this to intimidate you. I'm being your lawyer here.
谢谢，杰克 我觉得你们这帮人都是见鬼的疯子
Thanks, Jack. And I think the fucking bunch of you are certifiably insane.
你们的礼法让我看不顺眼
Your code of honor makes me want to beat the shit out of somebody.
别因为我穿同样的制服 就把我和他们混为一谈
Don't lump me in with them just because we wear the same uniform.
我是你的朋友 也认为你的当事人不该去监狱…
I'm your friend, and I don't think your clients belong in jail...
但我无权决定
but I don't get to make that decision.
我代表美国政府，不能带感情色彩或偏见
I represent the United States government without passion or prejudice.
我的当事人证据充分 你的酒
My client has a case. Here you go.
你该感谢我作为军事检察官提醒你…
I want you to acknowledge that the judge advocate has made you aware...
没有充分的证据想指控一名 海军陆战队军官犯有重罪会有什么后果
of the possible consequences involved in accusing a Marine officer... of a felony without proper evidence.
我听过这样的忠告
I've been so advised.
你是被逼上法庭的，丹尼
You got bullied into that courtroom, Danny.
所有人都给你压力，有道森，有盖洛维
By everyone. By Dawson, by Galloway.
见鬼，实际上我也有挑衅你
Shit, I practically dared you.
你父亲当年的盛名也在逼迫你步入法庭
You got bullied into that courtroom by the memory of a dead lawyer.
你是个下流卑鄙没种的对手，杰克
You're a lousy fucking softball player, Jack!
你的小伙子们完了，丹尼 我再也无能为力了
Your boys are going down, Danny. I can't stop it anymore.
肯德瑞克上尉，你认为 一等兵圣地亚哥是个好陆战队员吗？
Lieutenant Kendrick, in your opinion, was Private Santiago a good Marine?
我只能说他很一般
I'd say he was about average.
你在三份圣地亚哥的考核报告上签过名
You signed three proficiency and conduct reports on Santiago.
你在所有这些报告上 都是给予中等偏下的评语
On all three reports, you indicate a rating of below average.
是的，一等兵圣地亚哥的表现 是低于一般水平
Yes, Private Santiago was below average.
我看不出有必要再践踏一个死者的尊严
I did not see the need to trample on a man's grave.
我们非常赞同，但你是发过誓的
We appreciate that, but you're under oath now.
也许会令人不快，但我们是想了解真相
Unpleasant as it may be, we'd all just as soon hear the truth.
我知道我发过誓
I'm aware of my oath.
这是道森准下士最近的三份考核报告 上面有你的签名
These are the last three pro-con reports you signed for Lance Corporal Dawson.
两次被评为优异…
Dawson received two marks of exceptional...
但最后一份即六月九日 的报告上他得到的评语是中等偏下
but on this most recent report of June 9 he received a rating of below average.
我想讨论一下这最后一份报告 没问题
I'd like to discuss this last report. That would be fine.
道森准下士 从步兵学校毕业后的等级评定非常优秀
Lance Corporal Dawson's ranking after the school of infantry was perfect.
同班超过半数的人晋升为下士时…
Over half that class has since been promoted to full corporal...
道森还是个准下士
while Dawson has remained a lance corporal.
道森晋升受阻是因为最后这份报告吗？
Was Dawson's promotion held up because of this last report?
肯定是
I'm sure it was.
为什么这份报告 会给道森如此可怜的等级？
Do you recall why Dawson was given such a poor grade on this report?
我确实忘了
I'm sure I don't.
我手下有很多人，有很多报告要写
I have many men in my charge. I write many reports.
上尉，你是否能记起一名 叫柯蒂斯・贝尔的一等兵…
Lieutenant, do you recall an incident involving a P.F.C. Curtis Bell...
从军官俱乐部偷酒的事？
who'd been found stealing liquor from the Officers'Club?
是的，有这事
Yes, I do.
你是否向上级举报过？
Did you report Private Bell to proper authorities?
我床头有两本书…
I have two books at my bedside...
“海军陆战队员行为守则”和“圣经”
The Marine Corps Code of Conduct and The King james Bible.
我唯一知道的上级就是我的指挥官…
The only proper authorities I'm aware of are my commanding officer...
内森・Ｒ・杰赛普上校和上帝
Colonel Nathan R. Jessup and the Lord our God.
以你的说法，上尉，我可以理解为…
At your request, Lieutenant Kendrick, I can have the record reflect...
你不承认军事法庭也是你的上级
your lack of acknowledgement of this court as a proper authority.
反对，与本案无关 反对有效
Objection. Argumentative. Sustained.
请注意，律师
Watch yourself, counselor.
你向上级举报柯蒂斯・贝尔没有？
Did you report Private Bell to your superiors?
我记忆中一等兵贝尔是很优秀的…
I remember thinking very highly of Private Bell...
不希望看到他的履历因此而染上污点
not wanting to see his record tarnished by a formal charge.
你更愿意在单位内部解决是吗？
You preferred it be handled within the unit?
是的，确实如此
Yes, I most certainly did.
你知道什么是“红色条规”吗？ 是的，我知道
Do you know what a Code Red is? Yes, I do.
你曾下令执行过“红色条规”吗？ 不，我没有
Have you ever ordered a Code Red? No, I have not.
你是否曾命令道森和另两个部下…
Did you order Dawson and two other men to make sure that Private Bell...
看住贝尔，总共七天 除了水之外不给他任何食物或饮料？
received no food or drink, except water, for a period of seven days?
这是歪曲事实，中尉
That is a distortion of the truth, Lieutenant.
一等兵贝尔是被监禁在营房内
Private Bell was placed on barracks restriction.
有水和维他命作补充 而且我能向你保证…
He was given water and vitamin supplements, and I can assure you...
他的健康从未受到威胁
at no time was his health in danger.
我相信这对一等兵贝尔来说很有趣
I'm sure it was lovely for Private Bell.
但你有没有下令关禁闭呢？
But you did order the barracks restriction, didn't you?
有没有下令不提供食物呢？ 是的，我下过命令
You did order the denial of food? Yes, I did.
这种形式的处罚 可以认为是属于“红色条规”吗？
Wouldn't this form of discipline be considered a Code Red?
不
No
如果我传关达那摩湾的 其他四百七十八名陆战队员作证…
If I called the other 478 Marines at Guantanamo Bayto testify...
他们会认为这是“红色条规”吗？
would they consider it a Code Red?
证人不可能证实 其他四百七十八个人会怎么说
The witness can't possibly testify as to what 478 other men would say.
控方反对这一系列的提问 这些与本案无关…
We object to this entire line of questioning. It's argumentative...
是对证人的无端骚扰
and irrelevant badgering of the witness.
控方反对有效，凯菲中尉…
The government's objection is sustained, Lieutenant Kaffee...
我要提醒你 你正在询问的是一名海军军官…
and I would remind you that you're now questioning a Marine officer...
履历记录无可挑剔
with an impeccable service record.
谢谢，法官大人
Thank you, Your Honor.
上尉，道森最后那份报告 被给予中等偏下的评定…
Lieutenant, was Dawson given a rating of below average on this last report...
是因为你发觉他偷偷给贝尔食物吗？
because you learned he'd been sneaking food to Private Bell?
反对 别着急…上尉？
Object! Not so fast. Lieutenant?
道森准下士被给予中等偏下的评语…
Lance Corporal Dawson was given a below average rating...
是因为他违犯了军规
because he had committed a crime.
军规？他犯了什么军规？
A crime? What crime did he commit?
肯德瑞克上尉
Lieutenant Kendrick
道森给一个饥饿的人送食物 犯了哪条军规？
Dawson brought a hungry guy some food. What crime did he commit?
他违反了命令
He disobeyed an order.
因为他履行了自己的价值观…
And because he exercised his own set ofvalues...
作了与一名陆战队员健康有关的决定…
because he made a decision about the welfare of a Marine...
而这与你的命令有抵触，所以得受罚 是这样吗？
that was in conflict with your order, he was punished, is that right?
道森准下士违反了命令
Lance Corporal Dawson disobeyed an order.
可那不是真正的命令不是吗？
Yeah, but it wasn't a real order, was it?
毕竟现在是和平年代
After all, it's peacetime.
他没被派去守卫山头或是进攻滩头阵地
He wasn't being asked to secure a hill or advance on a beachhead.
我是说 一名具备道森这种能力的陆战队员…
I mean, surely a Marine of Dawson's intelligence...
完全可以自己决定哪些命令重要…
can be trusted to determine on his own which are the important orders...
哪些命令有可能…在道德上有疑义
and which orders might, say, be morally questionable?
肯德瑞克上尉？
Lieutenant Kendrick?
是这样吗？
Can he?
道森可以自己决定应该服从哪些命令吗？
Can Dawson determine on his own which orders he's going to follow?
不，他不能
No, he cannot.
柯蒂斯・贝尔的事让他受了教育，是吧？
A lesson he learned after the Curtis Bell incident, right?
我想是的 你确信是这样对吧？
I would think so. You know so, don't you?
反对 反对有效
Object! Sustained.
肯德瑞克上尉，最后一个问题
Lieutenant Kendrick, one final question.
如果你命令道森 对圣地亚哥执行“红色条规”…
If you had ordered Dawson to give Santiago a Code Red...
我特地命令手下… 他会再次违反命令吗？
I specifically ordered those men... Would he disobey you again?
上尉，不必作答 用不着回答，我问完了
Lieutenant, don't answer that! You don't have to. I'm through.
肯德瑞克上尉 你是否曾命令道森准下士…
Lieutenant Kendrick, did you order Lance Corporal Dawson...
和一等兵多尼 对威廉・圣地亚哥执行“红色条规”？
and Private Downey to give Willie Santiago a Code Red?
肯德瑞克上尉？
Lieutenant Kendrick?
不，我没有 谢谢
No, I did not. Thank you.
怎么样？
What's the word?
我拿到了指挥塔那天晚上的日志 杰赛普说的是事实
I got the tower chiefs log from that night. Jessup's telling the truth.
最早离开的航班是在早上六点 让我看看
6:00 a.m. Flight was the first plane. Let me see this.
今晚加班？ 是啊
Working late tonight? Oh, yeah.
十一点根本没有航班 你到底在搞什么鬼？
There wasn't a flight at 11:00. What the fuck are you trying to pull?
从关达那摩到美国最早的航班 是在二十三点
The first flight stateside left Guantanamo Bay at 2300.
凌晨两点过几分抵达安德鲁斯空军基地
It arrived at Andrews Air Force Base at a few minutes past 2:00.
是吗？那为什么指挥塔的日志没有记录？
Really? Then why isn't it listed in the tower chiefs log?
杰赛普
Jessup.
你是说他窜改了日志吗？
What are you telling me? He fixed the logbook?
也许他能更改起飞记录 但我可以证明曾有飞机降落过
Maybe he can make it so a plane didn't take off, but I can prove one landed.
我去安德鲁斯找记录
I'll get the logbook from Andrews.
你在安德鲁斯的日志上也发现不了什么
You're not gonna find anything in the Andrews logbook, either.
他能让整个航班消失吗？
He can make an entire flight disappear?
杰赛普就要被任命为安全委员会的主管了
Jessup is about to be appointed director of operations for the Security Council.
不知道怎么避开地雷 是休想得到那个位置的
You don't get to that position without knowing how to sidestep some land mines.
可他没法避开你
He's not gonna be able to sidestep you.
你不会还想让我出庭吧？
You don't still intend to put me on the stand?
星期四上午十点
Thursday morning, 10:00.
得找到能证实有那趟航班的人
There's gotta be someone who can testify to the flight.
这不象航空公司有固定的飞行时刻表
This isn't TWA. There isn't a regular flight schedule.
你知道每天有多少架飞机起起落落？
Do you have any idea how many planes take off and land every day?
地勤人员也记不住 那趟航班四周前的降落时间
A ground crew kid won't remember a flight that landed four weeks ago.
不去查怎么会知道呢？ 忘了那趟航班
How do you know if you don't check? Forget the flight!
马金森会证明杰赛普拒绝调走圣地亚哥
Markinson will testify that Jessup refused to transfer Santiago.
他会证明调令是伪造的，这就够了
He'll testify to the forged transfer, and that'll be enough.
加上多尼的证词应该够了
That and Downey's testimony really ought to be enough.
六号夜里你们为什么 进入圣地亚哥的房间？
Why did you go into Santiago's room on the night of the 6th?
对一等兵圣地亚哥 执行“红色条规”，夫人
To give Private Santiago a Code Red, ma'am.
你们为什么这样做？
Why did you give him a Code Red?
是Ｗ步兵警卫连 排长乔纳森-詹姆斯-肯德瑞克上尉…
I was ordered to give him a Code Red by the platoon commander...
下令对他执行“红色条规”
of Rifle Security Company Windward, Lieutenant Jonathan James Kendrick.
你们会没事的
You're gonna do fine.
你觉得会让我们很快回连队吗，夫人？
You think they'll let us go back to our platoon soon, ma'am?
绝对没问题
Absolutely.
记得提问的顺序吗？能肯定吗？
Do you remember the order of questions? Areyou sure?
简练一点，不然他听不懂就麻烦了
And we'll use small words,'cause he gets rattled ifhe doesn't understand.
我是说节奏要慢一点 我会的
I'm just saying go slow. I'm gonna go slow.
但要尽快把问题问完
And get him off as fast as you can.
怎么了？不会有问题的
What? It's gonna be fine.
尊敬的圣地亚哥先生和夫人…
Dear Mr. And Mrs. Santiago...
我是威廉的行政长官
I was William's executive officer.
我对令郎不太熟悉，只知道他叫什么名字
I knew your son vaguely, which is to say I knew his name.
那两个对令郎之死负有责任的人 的审判很快就有结果了
In a matter of time, the trial of the two men... charged with your son's death will be concluded...
你们素不相识的七男两女…
and seven men and two women whom you've never met...
将试着为令郎的死给出一个解释
will try to offer you an explanation as to why William is dead.
而我已经尽我所能来使真相大白于天下
For my part, I've done as much as I can to bring the truth to light.
事实上…
And the truth is this...
令郎的死只有一个原因…
Your son is dead for only one reason...
我阻止事态发展时不够强硬
I wasn't strong enough to stop it.
美国海军，马修-安德鲁-马金森中校 敬上
Always, Lieutenant Colonel Matthew Andrew Markinson... United States Marine Corps.
一等兵，我要你再向大家说一次
Private, I want you to tell us one last time.
你们为什么在九月六日夜里 去一等兵圣地亚哥的房间？
Why did you go to Private Santiago's room on the night of September 6?
是排长肯德瑞克上尉 命令我们去执行“红色条规”
A Code Red was ordered by my platoon commander... Lieutenant Jonathan James Kendrick.
谢谢
Thank you.
该你问了
Your witness.
一等兵，九月二日那一周的…
Private, the week of 2 September...
换岗记录显示 十六点以前你一直在三十九号哨岗
the switch log has you down at Post 39 until 1600.
是这样吗？
Is that correct?
是的，长官，记录一直做得很准确
I'm sure it is, sir. They keep that log pretty good.
三十九号哨岗离Ｗ连的营房有多远？
How far is it from Post 39 to the Windward Barracks?
有点距离，长官，得走一阵子
Well, it's a ways, sir. It's a hike.
搭乘越野车要多久？
About how far by Jeep?
他问这个干什么？ 十到十五分钟，长官
About ten or fifteen minutes, sir.
你曾步行过吗？
You ever had to walk it?
是的，长官 星期五那天，“临时司机”…
Yes, sir. That day, Friday. The pickup private...
我们都这么叫负责接送我们的二等兵…
That's what we call the guy who drops us off and picks us up...
同时也因为他能在“纽约城”泡到女孩子
also'cause he can get girls in New York City.
他到三十九号哨的时候爆胎了
The pickup private got a flat, sir, right at 39.
他一停车，胎就爆了，又没有备胎
He pulled up and, bam, blowout with no spare.
所以我们只好跑步回营房
So we had to double-time it back to the barracks.
既然越野车要花十到十五分钟，我猜…
And if it's about ten or fifteen minutes by Jeep, I'm guessing...
跑步至少要一个小时，对不对？
it must be a good hour by foot, am I right?
他和我刚好用了四十五分钟，长官
Pickup and me did it in 45 flat, sir.
不错啊
Not bad.
你说你们去袭击一等兵圣地亚哥…
You've said that your assault on Private Santiago...
是因为肯德瑞克上尉十六点二十分时…
was a result of an order that Lieutenant Kendrick gave you...
在你们的房间给你们下了命令，对不对？
in your barracks room at 1620, am I right?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
但你刚才说十六点四十五分之前 你们还没回到营房
But you just said that you didn't make it back to the barracks until 1645.
既然十六点四十五分之前 你还没回到营房…
Well, if you didn't make it back to the barracks until 1645...
那十六点二十分你怎么会在房间里？
how could you be in your room at 1620?
是这样，长官，车胎爆了…
Well, you see, sir, there was a blowout...
你有没有亲耳听到 肯德瑞克上尉下令执行“红色条规”？
Did you ever actually hear Lieutenant Kendrick order a Code Red?
哈罗德说…
Well, Hal said that...
一等兵，你有没有亲耳听到…
Private, did you ever actually hear...
肯德瑞克上尉下令执行“红色条规”？ 没有，长官
Lieutenant Kendrick order a Code Red?
请求暂时休庭 我要和我的当事人交换意见
I'd like to request a recess in order to confer with my client.
你为什么去圣地亚哥的房间？ 证人有他的权利
Why did you go into Santiago's room? The witness has rights!
证人早就知道他的权利 重复一下刚才的问题
The witness has been read his rights. The question will be repeated.
你为什么去圣地亚哥的房间？ 哈罗德
Why did you go into Santiago's room?
是道森要你去执行“红色条规”吗？ 哈罗德
Did Lance Corporal Dawson tell you to give Santiago a Code Red?
不要看他 哈罗德
Don't look at him! Hal!
回答上尉的问题
Answer the captaings question!
长官，是我的班长，美国海军 哈罗德-Ｗ-道森准下士给我的命令…
Yes, Captain, I was given an order by my squad leader... Lance Corporal Harold W. Dawson, United States Marine Corps...
所以我执行了
and I followed it.
你说他会去哪？
Where do you think he is?
对多尼而言，那就是肯德瑞克下的命令
As far as Downey was concerned, it was an order from Kendrick.
是不是亲耳听到都一样
It doesn't matter that he didn't hear it firsthand.
他不会关心两者之间的区别
He doesn't distinguish between the two.
丹尼，我很抱歉
Danny, I'm sorry.
不用担心
Don't worry about it.
山姆和我刚才谈到我们应该…
Sam and I were just talking about how all we really have to do...
找些能指认间接命令的证人
is call some witnesses who will talk about implied orders.
在盘问道森之前让多尼再次充当证人
Maybe we can put Downey back on the stand before we get to Dawson.
照这样干下去 我们能让道森为暗杀肯尼迪负责
If we work at it, we can get Dawson charged with the Kennedy assassination.
你喝了酒？
Are you drunk?
喝了不少
Pretty much.
我去多弄点咖啡 我们今天要忙到很晚才行
I'll put on a pot of coffee. We've got a long night's work ahead.
她要去弄咖啡
She's gonna make coffee.
真不赖
That's nice.
多尼当时不在房间里
Downey wasn't in his room.
根本不在
Wasn't even there.
那是条非常重要的信息，你认为呢？
That was an important piece of information, don't you think?
丹尼，这是个打击，对此我很抱歉
Danny, it was a setback, and I'm sorry.
但还能补救，我们有马金森
But we fix it, and move on to Markinson.
马金森死了
Markinson's dead.
你真得感谢那些联邦密探，伙计
You really gotta hand it to those Federal Marshals, boy.
他不是用自己的鞋带上吊…
It's not like he hanged himself by his shoelaces...
也不是用偷藏的黄油刀割腕
or slashed his wrists with a concealed butter knife.
这家伙…
This guy...
身着全套制服，站在房间的中央…
got into full dress uniform, stood in the middle of that room...
从他的枪套里拔出一支蹭亮的手枪…
drew a nickel-plated pistol from his holster...
朝自己的嘴里开了一枪
and fired a bullet into his mouth.
既然我们已经没有证人了 我想我该喝上一点
Anyway, since we seem to be out of witnesses, I thought I'd drink a little.
我还是认为我们能赢
I still think we can win.
或许你也该喝点
Maybe you should drink a little.
我们明早去找伦道夫法官 要求押后二十四小时再审
We'll go to Randolph in the morning and make a motion for a 24-hour continuance.
我们这样做是为什么？ 传讯杰赛普上校
Why would we want to do that? To subpoena Colonel Jessup.
什么？ 别急，听我说完
What? Listen for a second. Hear me out.
我不想听，更不想听你说完
I won't listen, and I won't hear you out.
勇气可嘉，但毫无意义
Your passion is compelling, Jo. It's also useless.
劳登・多尼今天需要一个庭审律师
Louden Downey needed a trial lawyer today.
胆小鬼
You're chickenshit.
你想用今天的事作借口认输吗？
You're gonna use what happened today as an excuse to give up.
结束了
It's over.
你干嘛要向杰赛普要那份调令？
Why did you ask Jessup for the transfer order?
为什么？ 这有什么？
In Cuba. Why? What does it matter?
我想要那份该死的调令 胡说
I wanted the damn transfer order! Bullshit.
想要的话在五角大楼任何部门都能找到
You could've gotten it by calling any department at the Pentagon.
你不是想要那份调令 你是想看看杰赛普的反应
You didn't want the transfer order. You wanted to see Jessup's reaction.
直觉告诉你有内情 而马金森证实了这一点
You had an instinct, and it was confirmed by Markinson.
我们要让杰赛普出庭了结此事
Let's put Jessup on the stand and end this thing!
让杰赛普出庭又能有什么好结果呢？
What possible good could come from putting Jessup on the stand?
是他让肯德瑞克下的“红色条规”令
He told Kendrick to order the Code Red.
是吗？那太好了，你凭什么这么说？
He did? That's great! Why didn't you say so?
显然你能证明这一点
And of course you have proof of that!
对不起，我忘了 你因病缺席了法律学校的法律课
Oh, I'm sorry. I forgot. You were sick the day they taught law at law school.
让他出庭作证，让他自己说出来
You put him on the stand, and you get it from him.
让他自己说出来，是啊，没问题
Oh, we get it from him! Yes! No problem!
杰赛普上校，是不是你 下令对圣地亚哥执行“红色条规”？
Colonel Jessup, isn't it true that you ordered the Code Red on Santiago?
听着，我们都有点… 对不起，时间到
Listen, we're all a little... I'm sorry. Your time's run out.
该怎么打发输家呢？让我们的被告…
What do we have for the losers? Well, for our defendants...
在莱文沃斯堡（监狱）休养一辈子
it's a lifetime at exotic Fort Leavenworth.
至于辩护律师凯菲中尉…
And for Defense Counsel Kaffee...
让他上军事法庭
it's a court-martial!
没错，伙计，因为共谋及作伪证…
Yes, Johnny, after falsely accusing...
无端指控一名功勋卓著的海军军官…
a highly decorated Marine officer... of conspiracy and perjury...
凯菲中尉会有一份美好的前途…
Lieutenant Kaffee will have a long and prosperous career...
去沃克科洛布女子学校 执教打字机维修
teaching typewriter maintenance at the Rocco Clubo School for Women.
谢谢你参与 “我们该不该听从笨蛋的劝告？”的演出
Thank you for playing "Should we or should we not... follow the advice of the galactically stupid?"
很抱歉我毁了你的大好前程
I'm sorry I lost your set of steak knives.
别收拾了
Stop cleaning up.
山姆，别收拾了
想喝点吗？
Want a drink? Yeah.
你父亲以你为荣吗？ 别给自己太多压力
Is your father proud of you? Don't do this to yourself.
我敢说一定是
I'll bet he is.
我打赌他会不厌其烦地对邻居和亲戚说…
I'll bet he bores the shit out of the neighbors and relatives.
山姆上了'法律评论'栏目 他接了个大案子
"Sam's made LawReview. He's got a big case he's making.
他上庭了，正在为一个案子作辩护律师
He's arguing. He's making an argument."
我父亲一定很高兴看到我从法律学校毕业
I think my father would've enjoyed seeing me graduate from law school.
他一定为此欣喜若狂
I think he would've liked that an awful lot.
我有没有告诉过你 我在学校时写过一篇关于你父亲的论文？
Did I ever tell you I wrote a paper about your father in college? Yeah?
他是有史以来最好的律师之一
One of the best trial lawyers ever.
是的，的确是
Yes, he was.
如果我是道森和多尼…
If I were Dawson and Downey and I had a choice...
要从你和你父亲当中选代表律师的话…
between you or your father to represent me in this case...
不管什么时候我都会选你
I'd choose you any day of the week and twice on Sunday.
要知道你把肯德瑞克给镇住了
You should've seen yourself thunder away at Kendrick.
你会让杰赛普出庭吗？
Would you put Jessup on the stand?
不会
No
你觉得我父亲会这样做吗？ 以我们掌握的证据而言吗？
Do you think my father would have? With the evidence we got?
绝对不会
Not in a million years.
但问题是…现在所有的人都知道…
But here's the thing... and there's really know way of getting around this...
既不是你父亲也不是我 在担任首席辩护律师来处理…
Neither Lyle Kaffee nor Sam Weinberg are lead counsel for the defense...
这起政府起诉道森和多尼的案子
in the matter of U... S. V. Dawson and Downey.
所以唯一的问题就是…你会怎么做？
So there's really only one question... What would you do?
乔，上车，乔安妮，求你上车吧
Jo, get in the car. Joanne, please get in the car.
听我说…
Look...
我很抱歉冲你发火，我为我说的话道歉
I apologize. I was angry. I'm sorry about what I said.
我会让杰赛普出庭作证
I'm gonna put Jessup on the stand.
你觉得我们该怎么做？
What do you suggest we do?
证明杰赛普伪造了调令
I say we hit Jessup with the phony transfer order.
上哪去找证人？
What's a transfer order without a witness?
我们有证人 已经死了
We have a witness. A dead witness.
对一个次席律师来说这确实是个问题
In the hands of a lesser attorney, that would be a problem.
瞧瞧吧，昨晚他还在借酒消愁…
Look at this. Last night he's swimming in Jack Daniels...
现在却无所不能了
and now he can leap tall buildings in a single bound.
我又上好发条了，你们都坐好
I'm getting my second wind. Sit down, both of you.
很好，杰赛普让肯德瑞克 下“红色条规”令，肯德瑞克照做了
Good. Jessup told Kendrick to order the Code Red. Kendrick did.
当事人执行了命令，这我们无法证实
Our clients followed the order. The cover-up isn't our case.
要赢的话，得让杰赛普 告诉陪审团是他下的“红色条规”令
To win, Jessup needs to tell the court members that he ordered the Code Red.
你觉得你能让他说出来吗？ 我觉得他想说出来
You think you can get him to say it? I think he wants to say it.
他肯定因为不能说出来而恼火
I think he's pissed off that he's got to hide from us.
他想说出是他作的决定 这样事情就能解决
I think he wants to say that he made a command decision, and that's the end.
他吃早餐时三百码外…
He eats breakfast 300 yards away...
有四千名训练有素的古巴人想干掉他
from 4,000 Cubans that are trained to kill him.
没人能干涉他带兵的方式
No one's gonna tell him how to run his unit.
至少穿着娘娘腔制服的“哈佛嘴”不能
Least of all the Harvard mouth in his faggotywhite uniform.
我得激怒他，让他进行反击…
I need to shake him, put him on the defensive...
然后领着他自掘坟墓
and lead him right where he's dying to go.
就这样？这就是计划？ 这就是计划
That's it? That's the plan? That's the plan.
你打算怎么做？ 还没头绪
How are you gonna do it? I have no idea.
我需要我的球棒 需要什么？
I need my bat. Your what?
拿着球棒我的思路更敏捷，它在哪？
I think better with my bat. Where's my bat?
我把它放在壁橱里了 你把它放在壁橱里了？
I put it in the closet. You put it in the closet?
我被它绊了一下 永远别把它放到壁橱里
I was tripping on it. Don't ever put that bat in the closet.
拿着球棒能让他思路更敏捷？ 我能理解
He thinks better with his bat? I can understand that.
呆在这，我去趟办公室
Stay here. I'm going to the office for a while.
拿着球棒确实能给他灵感
He does think better with that bat.
古巴关达那摩湾 打出电话记录
山姆，我要你替我办件事
Sam, I need you to do something for me.
怎么了？ 得去趟安德鲁斯
What's going on? Gotta go out to Andrews.
山姆呢？ 还在路上
Where's Sam? He's on his way.
他找到人没有？ 找到了
Did he get the guys? Yeah.
能和你聊几句吗？
Listen, can I talk to you for a second?
当然，没问题
Oh, yeah, sure.
你感觉怎么样？
How you feeling?
我看杰赛普今天要举手投降了
Well, I think Jessup's gonna have his hands full today.
听我说，丹尼…
Listen, Danny...
你今天上去的时候…
when you're out there today...
如果感觉计划不能成功…
if you feel like it's not gonna happen...
如果你觉得他不会说出来…
if you feel like he's not gonna say it...
就别勉强行事
don't go for it.
不然你会惹上麻烦
You could get in trouble.
我是内政部的特别律师…
I'm special counsel for Internal Affairs...
我知道那会惹来多少麻烦
and I'm telling you you could get in a lot of trouble.
等等，盖洛维少校…
Wait, Lieutenant Commander Galloway...
你不是在奉劝我放弃这个重要证人吧？
you're not suggesting that I back off a material witness?
如果你觉得不能引他上钩的话，是的
If you think you can't get him, yeah.
全体起立
All rise.
山姆呢？ 就快到了
Where's Sam? He's on his way.
传第一位证人 他在哪？
Call your first witness. Where is he?
他会来的 中尉
He'll be here. Lieutenant.
传你的证人
Call your witness.
辩方传唤内森・杰赛普上校
Defense calls Colonel Nathan Jessup.
杰赛普上校，请举起你的右手，长官
Colonel Jessup, would you raise your right hand please, sir?
你能发誓你在法庭上所说的一切…
Do you solemnly swear that the testimony you will give in this court-martial...
完全属实，绝无虚假吗？
will be the truth, the whole truth and nothing but the truth?
我发誓
Yes, I do.
请坐下，长官
Have a seat please, sir.
请说出你的姓名，军衔和现任职务 以便法庭记录
Would you state your name, rank and current billet for the record, sir?
内森・Ｒ・杰赛普，上校…
Colonel Nathan R. Jessup, commanding officer...
古巴关达那摩湾 美国海军陆战队指挥官
Marine Ground Forces, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.
谢谢，长官 他还没来
Thank you, sir. He's not here.
上校，你得知圣地亚哥 写给海军调查处的那封信时…
Colonel, when you learned of Santiago's letter to the N.I. S...
曾和你手下两位高级军官开过会
you had a meeting with your two senior officers.
是这样吗？ 是的
Is that right? Yes.
是排长乔纳森・肯德瑞克上尉…
The platoon commander, Lieutenant Jonathan Kendrick...
和行政长官马修・马金森中校吗？
and the executive officer, Lieutenant Colonel Matthew Markinson.
是的
Yes.
现在马金森中校已经死了，是这样吗？
And at present Colonel Markinson is dead. Is that right?
反对，不知辩方律师这是什么意思
Objection. I'd like to know just what the defense counsel is implying.
意思很简单，就是马金森中校已经死了
I'm implying simply that at present Colonel Markinson is not alive.
杰赛普上校 用不着在法庭上确认这个消息
Colonel Jessup doesn't need to appear in court to confirm that information.
我是想确认证人是否知道两天前 中校用一支点四五手枪自尽了
I just wasn't sure the witness was aware that two days ago... the colonel took his own life with a.45-caliber pistol.
证人知道了，法庭知道了…
The witness is aware, the court is aware...
现在陪审团也知道了
and now the court members are aware.
谢谢你为我们带来这个消息
We thank you for bringing this to our attention.
继续吧，中尉
Move on, Lieutenant...
好的，法官大人
Yes, sir.
上校，你在会上 给肯德瑞克上尉下过命令是吗？
Colonel, you gave Lieutenant Kendrick an order at this meeting, right?
我让肯德瑞克告诉他的手下 不许碰圣地亚哥
I told Kendrick to tell his men that Santiago wasn't to be touched.
你是不是也给马金森中校下过命令？
And did you give an order to Colonel Markinson as well?
我命令马金森立刻将圣地亚哥调离基地
I ordered Markinson to have Santiago transferred off the base immediately.
为什么？
Why?
我担心一旦信的内容泄露出去 他可能会有生命危险
I felt his life might be in danger once word of the letter got out.
致命的危险？
Grave danger?
还能是什么？
Is there another kind?
上校，这是你和马金森联合签名的调令…
Colonel, we have the transfer order that you and Markinson co-signed...
命令圣地亚哥乘第二天凌晨六点的航班 离开关达那摩
ordering that Santiago be on a flight leaving Guantanamo at 6:00 the next day.
那是最早的航班吗？ 六点是最早飞离基地的航班
Was that the first flight? The 0600 was the first flight.
你是今早乘飞机来华盛顿的对吗？
You flew up to Washington this morning. Is that right?
我注意到你今天是穿着高级制服上的法庭
I notice you'rewearing your class "A" dress uniform in court today.
彼此彼此，中尉 你在飞机上也是这身穿着吗？
As are you, Lieutenant. Did you wear that on the plane?
法官大人，这与本案有什么关…
Please the court, is this dialogue relevant to anything...
辩方难得有机会请这位证人作证
Defense didn't have the opportunity to depose this witness.
我想多问几个问题 请注意提问范围
I'd ask for a little latitude. A very little latitude.
上校？
Colonel?
我在飞机上穿的是便服
I wore utilities on the plane.
不过你带着军装是吧？ 是的
You brought your dress uniform? Yes.
那么牙刷，剃须刀，内衣呢？ 法官大人…
Toothbrush, shaving kit, underwear? Your Honor!
难道上校的内衣也是国家机密吗？
Is the colonel's underwear a matter of national security?
两位，你最好尽快问完这些，中尉
Gentlemen! You better get somewhere fast with this, Lieutenant.
是，大人，上校？
Yes, sir. Colonel?
我带了一套替换衣服和一些私人用品
I brought a change of clothes and some personal items.
谢谢
Thank you.
道森和多尼在六号晚上被拘捕后…
After Dawson and Downey's arrest on the night of the sixth...
圣地亚哥的房间就被封了 这是房内的物品清单
Santiago's barracks were sealed off and its contents inventoried.
四条迷彩裤，三件卡其衬衣…
"Four pairs camouflage pants, three long-sleeve khaki shirts...
三双靴子，四双军袜，三件军用Ｔ恤…
three pairs of boots, four pairs green socks, three green T-shirts..."
法官大人，我们要一直这么问下去吗？
Please the court, is there a question anywhere in our future?
凯菲中尉，我得要求你提出你的问题
Lieutenant Kaffee, I have to ask you to state your question.
为什么圣地亚哥没有收拾行李？
I'm wondering why Santiago wasn't packed.
我稍后会告诉大家，先来看看这个
I'll tell you what. We'll get back to that one in a minute.
这是过去二十四小时 从你们基地打出的所有电话记录
This is a record of all phone calls made from your base in the past 24 hours.
在被传唤来华盛顿之后，你打过三个电话
After being subpoenaed to Washington, you made three calls.
你熟悉这些号码吗？
Do you recognize those number, sir?
一个打给维州匡迪科基地的菲茨上校
I called Colonel Fitzhughes in Quantico, Virginia.
让他知道我要来这
I wanted to let him know that I would be in town.
第二个是打给众议院军事委员会 的里奇蒙德议员…
The second call was to arrange a meeting with Congressman Richmond...
和他商量见一下面
of the House Armed Services Committee.
第三个是打给我妹妹伊莉莎白
And the third call was to my sister Elizabeth.
为什么要打这个电话，长官？
Why did you make that call, sir?
我想请她今晚一起吃晚饭
I thought she might like to have dinner tonight.
我会制止的 这些是九月六日从关达那摩…
I'm gonna stop this. These are phone records from Gitmo...
打出的电话记录，而这是圣地亚哥…
for September 6, and these are 14 letters...
在九个月内写的十四封信…
that Santiago wrote in nine months...
请求…事实上是乞求…调离
requesting... in fact, begging... for a transfer.
在得知终于被允许调离的消息之后…
Upon hearing the news that he was finally getting his transfer...
圣地亚哥非常兴奋 知道他给多少人打过电话吗？
Santiago was so excited that do you know how many people he called?
没给任何人打过
Zero. Nobody.
没有一个电话告知他的父母他要回家了
Not one call to his parents saying he was coming home.
没有一个电话打给朋友说 “你能来机场接我吗”
Not one call to a friend, saying, "Can you pick me up at the airport?"
半夜时他在床上睡着了，依你所说…
He was asleep in his bed at midnight, and according to you...
他六小时后就要上飞机
he was getting on a plane in six hours.
可他所有的东西 还整整齐齐地放在壁橱里…
Yet everything he owned was hanging neatly in his closet...
整整齐齐地叠放在扁条箱里
and folded neatly in his footlocker.
你只离开一天 就收拾了行李并打了三个电话
You were leaving for one day. You packed a bag and made three calls.
而圣地亚哥离开后这辈子都不会再回来…
Santiago was leaving for the rest of his life...
但他没打一个电话…
and he hadn't called a soul...
没收拾一件物品
and he hadn't packed a thing.
这你能解释吗？
Can you explain that?
事实是根本没有调令
The fact is, there was no transfer order.
圣地亚哥哪都不会去，是不是，上校？
Santiago wasn't going anywhere. Isn't that right, Colonel?
反对，法官大人，显然凯菲中尉意图…
Objection. Your Honor, it's obvious that Lieutenant Kaffee's intention...
诽谤一位高级海军军官…
is the smear a high-ranking Marine officer...
希望以这种无礼的举动来达到他的目的
in the hope that the mere appearance of impropriety will win him points.
大人，我请求对凯菲中尉予以惩戒…
It's my recommendation, sir, that Lieutenant Kaffee be reprimanded...
以此向证人表示法庭最诚恳的歉意
and the witness be excused with the court's deepest apologies.
驳回请求… 你的反对已记入笔录
Overruled. Your objection is noted.
上校？
Colonel?
很可笑吗，长官？
Is this funny, sir?
不，不是可笑，是可悲
No, it's not. It's tragic.
可以回答吗？ 当然
Do you have an answer? Absolutely.
我得说，我没有这见鬼的第一线索
My answer is, I don't have the first damn clue.
也许他习惯早起，愿意在早上收拾行李
Maybe he was an early riser and liked to pack in the morning.
也许他根本没什么朋友
And maybe he didn't have any friends.
我是受过教育，但我恐怕答不出…
I'm an educated man, but I'm afraid I can't speak intelligently...
关于威廉・圣地亚哥出行习惯的智力题
about the travel habits of William Santiago.
我只知道他已经被安排在六点离开基地
What I do know is that he was set to leave the base at 0600.
现在，难道叫我到这来 就是为了回答这些问题吗？
Now, are these really the questions that I was called here to answer?
电话以及扁条箱？
Phone calls and footlockers?
请告诉我你还想知道些什么，中尉
Please tell me that you have something more, Lieutenant.
这次审判将决定两名陆战队员的命运
These two Marines are on trial for their lives.
请告诉我他们的律师 不会将希望寄托在电话清单上
Please tell me that their lawyer hasn't pinned their hopes to a phone bill.
你还有其他问题要问吗，律师？
Do you have any other questions for me, counselor?
凯菲中尉？
Lieutenant Kaffee?
中尉，你还有什么问题要问证人吗？
Lieutenant, do you have anything further for this witness?
谢谢，丹尼，我喜欢华盛顿
Thanks, Danny. I love Washington.
抱歉，我还没让你走呢
Excuse me. I didn't dismiss you.
你说什么？
I beg your pardon?
我的盘问还没有结束，坐下
I'm not through with my examination. Sit down.
上校 什么意思？
Colonel. What's that?
你该称呼我 “上校” 或 “长官”
I'd appreciate it if you'd address me as "colonel" or "sir."
这是我应得的尊重
I believe I've earned it.
辩方律师应该称呼证人 “上校” 或 “长官”
Defense counsel will address the witness as "colonel" or "sir."
我不知道你管理的是什么鬼单位
I don't know what the hell kind of unit you're running here.
证人应该称呼法官 “法官大人” 或者 “庭上”
The witness will address this court as "judge" or "your honor."
我很肯定这是我应得的尊重 请坐，上校
I'm quite certain I've earned it. Take your seat, Colonel.
你现在想讨论什么？我最喜欢的颜色吗？
What do you want to discuss now? My favorite color?
上校，最早离开基地的航班是在六点吗？
Colonel, the 6:00 a.m. Flight was the first one off the base?
是的
Yes.
没有航班在七小时前离开…
There wasn't a flight that left seven hours earlier...
并于凌晨两点降落在安德鲁斯吗？
and landed at Andrews Air Force Base at 2:00 a. M?
中尉，我们不是问过这个问题了吗？
Lieutenant, I think we've covered this, haven't we?
法官大人，这些是…
Your Honor, these are the tower chiefs logs...
关达那摩和安德鲁斯指挥塔的飞行日志
for both Guantanamo Bay and Andrews Air Force Base.
关达那摩没有航班在二十三点离开的记录
The Guantanamo log lists no flight that left at 11:00 p.m.
安德鲁斯也没有航班在两点降落的记录
The Andrews log lists no flight that landed at 2:00 a.m.
辩方希望能从两个基地得到证实
I'd like to admit them as defense exhibits Alpha and Bravo.
什么意思？ 你想证实一趟从没有过的航班吗？
I don't understand. You're admitting evidence of a flight that never existed.
我们相信有，大人
We believe it did, sir.
辩方请求传空军 奥马雷和罗德瑞格作证
Defense will be calling Airmen Cecil O'Malley and Anthony Rodriguez.
他们是七号两点种时当班的地勤人员
They were working the ground crew at Andrews at 2:00 a.m. On the 7th.
他们不在证人名单上 第三度答辩证人…
These men weren't on the list. Rebuttal witnesses, Your Honor...
是特许被传唤 在直接盘问下提供证词的
called specifically to refute testimony offered under direct examination.
请求通过 真是荒谬
I'll allow the witnesses. This is ridiculous.
上校，刚才… 看在上帝份上，查查指挥塔的飞行日志吧
Colonel, a moment ago... Check the tower logs, for God's sake!
现在有空军可以证实，长官
We'll get to the airmen in just a minute, sir.
你刚才说曾命令肯德瑞克…
A moment ago you said that you ordered Lieutenant Kendrick...
告诉他的手下不许碰圣地亚哥
to tell his men that Santiago wasn't to be touched.
没错
That's right.
但他是不是清楚你的命令？
And Lieutenant Kendrick was clear on what you wanted?
完全清楚
Crystal.
他有没有可能忽视这个命令？
Any chance Lieutenant Kendrick ignored the order?
忽视这个命令？
Ignored the order?
他有没有可能忘记呢？ 不
Any chance he forgot about it?
有没有可能他离开你的办公室后说 “老头子错了”呢？
Any chance Lieutenant Kendrick left your office and said, "The old man is wrong"?
不
No
当肯德瑞克上尉告诉手下…
When Lieutenant Kendrick spoke to the platoon...
不许碰圣地亚哥时 他们有没有可能当成耳边风？
and ordered them not to touch Santiago, any chance they ignored him?
你曾在步兵团服过役吗，小子？
You ever served in an infantry unit, son?
没有，长官 曾经上过前线吗？
No, sir. Ever served in a forward area?
没有，长官 有没有把性命交给过别人…
Ever put your life in another man's hands?
或让别人把性命托付给你？ 没有，长官
Asked him to put his life in yours?
我们要服从命令，小子
We follow orders, son.
得服从命令，不然就会出人命
We follow orders, or people die.
就这么简单，听明白了吗？
It's that simple. Are we clear?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
听明白没有？
Are we clear?
完全明白
Crystal.
在我盘问奥马雷和罗德瑞格之前 还有个问题
I have just one more question before I call Airmen O'Malley and Rodriguez.
既然你下了命令不许碰圣地亚哥…
If you gave an order that Santiago wasn't to be touched...
而你的命令总是能得到遵从…
and your orders are always followed...
那圣地亚哥为什么会有危险？
then why would Santiago be in danger?
为什么他必须被调离基地呢？
Why would it be necessary to transfer him off the base?
圣地亚哥是一名不合格的陆战队员
Santiago was a substandard Marine.
他被调走… 你刚才可没这样说
He was being transferred... That's not what you said!
你说要调走他是因为他有生命危险 是的
You said he was being transferred because he was in grave danger.
我说 “致命的危险吗？” 你说 “还能是什么？”
I said, "Grave danger?" You said, "Is there any other kind?"
我记得我说过什么 我可以念给你听
I recall what I said. I can have it read back to you.
我知道我说过什么，用不着念给我听
I know what I said! I don't have to have it read back to me.
那为什么有两项命令？上校？
Then why the two orders? Colonel?
有时候那些手下会自作主张
Sometimes men take matters into their own hands.
你说得很清楚，你的部下决不会自作主张
You've made it clear that your men never take matters into their own hands.
他们得服从命令，否则会出人命
Your men follow orders, or people die.
那圣地亚哥应不应该有危险呢？
So Santiago should have been in danger, should he?
你这个无礼的小杂种 大人，我请求休庭
You snotty little bastard. I'd like to ask for a recess.
我要求证人回答这个问题 请证人回答问题
I'd like an answer to the question. The court will wait for an answer.
既然肯德瑞克曾经下令…
If Lieutenant Kendrick gave an order...
不许碰圣地亚哥…
that Santiago wasn't to be touched...
那他为什么非得调走？
then why did he have to be transferred?
上校？
Colonel?
肯德瑞克下“红色条规”令 是因为你授意他那样去做
Lieutenant Kendrick ordered the Code Red because that's what you told him to do!
反对 然后你却让他们做替罪羊
Object! And then you cut these guys loose!
我要告你藐视法庭 你还窜改了飞行日志
I'll hold you in contempt. You doctored the logbook!
该死的，凯菲 是你在藐视法庭
Damn it, Kaffee! Consider yourself in contempt.
杰赛普上校 是你下的“红色条规”令吗？
Colonel Jessup, did you order the Code Red?
你不必回答这个问题 我要回答
You don't have to answer that. I'll answer the question.
你想要答案？ 我有这个权利
You want answers? I think I'm entitled!
你想知道答案？ 我想知道事实
You want answers? I want the truth!
你受不了这个事实
You can't handle the truth!
小子，我们生活的世界 需要有人手持武器来守卫边疆
Son, we live in a world that has walls... and those walls have to be guarded by men with guns.
谁来守卫？是你？ 还是你，温伯格中尉？
Who's gonna do it? You? You, Lieutenant Weinberg?
我的责任比你们能想象到的要重要得多
I have a greater responsibility than you can possibly fathom.
你为圣地亚哥抱屈 却来折腾这些海军陆战队员
You weep for Santiago, and you curse the Marines.
你有幸不必知道我知道的事…
You have the luxury of not knowing what I know...
圣地亚哥的死固然是个悲剧 但可能拯救了更多的性命
that Santiago's death, while tragic, probably saved lives.
至于我的存在方式，对你来说是怪异 和不可理解的，但却是在拯救生命
And my existence, while grotesque and incomprehensible to you, saves lives!
你不想面对这个事实 是因为你未曾提起的潜意识里…
You don't want the truth because deep down you don't talk about...
你需要我来保家卫国
you want me on that wall.
You need me on that wall!
我们惯用的词语是尊严，军规，忠诚
We use words like honor, code, loyalty.
对这些词语我们不惜用生命来捍卫
We use these words as the backbone of a life spent defending something.
你们却拿来当儿戏
You use them as a punch line.
我既没有时间也没有兴趣 向你这种人作解释
I have neither the time nor the inclination to explain myself...
你在我提供的自由被褥下高枕无忧 却反过来质疑…
to a man who rises and sleeps under the blanket of the freedom I provide...
我提供自由的方式
and then questions the manner in which I provide it!
我看你最好是说声谢谢然后滚到一边去
I would rather you just said thank you and went on your way.
否则，我建议你拿上武器去站岗
Otherwise, I suggest you pick up a weapon and stand a post.
不然休想我给你 你自以为该有的什么鬼权利
Either way, I don't give a damn what you think you are entitled to!
是你下的“红色条规”令吗？
Did you order the Code Red?
我身负重任… 是你下的命令吗？
I did the job... Did you order the Code Red?
该死的，没错，是我
You're goddamned right I did!
法官大人，我提议让陪审团回避…
Please the court, I suggest the members be dismissed...
然后直接依据39-Ａ条款开庭
so that we can move to an immediate Article 39-A session.
这是证人的权利
The witness has rights.
罗斯上尉？
Captain Ross?
杰克？
Jack?
请陪审团到休息室等候进一步指示
The members of the court will retire to an anteroom until further instructed.
全体起立
All rise.
到底怎么回事？上校，怎么回事？
What the hell is this? Colonel, what's going on?
我是履行职责，以后也会这样做
I did my job. I'd do it again.
我得赶飞机回我的基地了
I'm gonna get on a plane and go on back to my base.
你哪都不能去，上校 宪兵，保护好上校
You're not going anywhere, Colonel. M.P. S, guard the colonel.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
罗斯上尉 这是搞什么鬼？
Captain Ross. What the hell is this?
杰赛普上校，你有权保持沉默
Colonel Jessup, you have the right to remain silent.
是指控我有罪吗？我犯了什么罪？
I'm being charged with a crime? Is that what this is?
我被指控有罪吗？ 你有权找一位律师
I'm being charged with a crime? You have a right to consult a lawyer.
荒谬，真是荒谬 你可以自已指定一名律师
This is funny. That's what this is. This lawyer may be appointed by you.
我要挖出你的眼睛，用你的头骨当便壶
I'm gonna rip the eyes out of your head and piss in your dead skull!
你毁了海军陆战队
You fucked with the wrong Marine!
杰赛普上校 你明白我刚才宣读的权利了吗？
Colonel Jessup, do you understand these rights as I have just read them?
你们这些混蛋
You fucking people.
你们不知道怎样保家卫国
You have no idea how to defend a nation.
你今天的作为只会危害到国家，凯菲
All you did was weaken a country today, Kaffee.
这就是你干的好事
That's all you did.
你将人民的生命置于危险之中 做你的美梦去吧，小子
You put people's lives in danger. Sweet dreams, son.
别叫我小子
Don't call me son.
我是美国海军中的一名律师和军官…
I'm a lawyer and an officer in the United States Navy...
你被逮捕了，狗娘养的
and you're under arrest, you son of a bitch.
证人可以退下了
The witness is excused.
全体起立
All rise.
陪审团有结果了吗？
Have the members reached a verdict?
是的，大人
We have, sir.
道森准下士和一等兵多尼
Lance Corporal Dawson and Private First Class Downey.
谋杀罪名，陪审团认为该项指控…
On the charge of murder, the members find the accused...
罪名不成立
not guilty.
共谋谋杀罪名…
On the charge of conspiracy to commit murder...
陪审团认为该项指控罪名不成立
the members find the accused not guilty.
对一名海军陆战队员行为不当罪名…
On the charge of conduct unbecoming a United States Marine...
陪审团认为该项指控罪名成立
the members find the accused guilty as charged.
据此所判刑期已于关押期间服满…
The accused are hereby sentenced to time already served...
并勒令从海军陆战队不荣誉解职
and you are ordered to be dishonorably discharged from the Marine Corps.
现在宣布退庭
This court-martial is adjourned.
全体起立
All rise.
那是什么意思？
What does that mean?
哈罗德
Harold
那是什么意思？
What did that mean?
我没明白，杰赛普上校都说了 是他下的“红色条规”令
I don't understand. Colonel Jessup said he ordered the Code Red.
我知道 他都承认了，我们没做错什么
I know. What did we do wrong?
这事没那么简单 我们没做错什么
It's not that simple. We did nothing wrong!
不，我们有错
Yeah, we did.
我们本该为那些没有自卫能力的人而战斗
We were supposed to fight for people who couldn't fight for themselves.
我们本该为圣地亚哥而战斗
We were supposed to fight for Willie.
我要带他们去人事处办些手续
I have to take these men over to personnel for some paperwork.
哈罗德
Harold
长官？
Sir?
你用不着手臂上的臂章来证明你的尊严
You don't need to wear a patch on your arm to have honor.
立正
attention hand
向长官致敬
There's an officer on deck.
空军奥马雷和罗德瑞格…
Airmen Cecil O'Malley and Anthony Rodriguez...
到底是来作什么证？
What exactly were these guys gonna testify to?
如果没弄错，他们是来宣誓证明…
Unless I'm mistaken, they were both gonna testify under oath...
他们确实什么都记不起来了
that they had absolutely no recollection of anything.
重要的证人 而且很帅，你觉得呢？
Strong witnesses. And handsome too, don't you think?
回见，我得去逮捕肯德瑞克
I'll see you around campus. I gotta go arrest Kendrick.
代我向他问好
Tell him I say hi.
我会的
Will do.